Hello everyone.
In this Part, we'll continue with
Price Action, focusing on Support and Resistance.
After we've learned and understood about candlesticks
from
the previous Parts
whether it's reading Momentum, reading candlesticks like we're telling a story
like scenes in a movie
battlefield, or whatever comparison you want to make.
Now let's continue with Support and Resistance.
This will make reading our charts
or Price Action, which is
the action of price, the movement of price
much clearer than reading
candlesticks alone.
Let's get started.
Price Action isn't just about Support and Resistance.
There are about 3-5 patterns.
I'll show you the really interesting ones.
First of all, Support and Resistance
Type 1: Horizontal.
The word horizontal, a horizontal level like this.
First, view it as a price zone. The concept is to see it as a price zone, not as a single line or single price.
View it as a price range, as a zone, covering an area.
If it's above, we call it Resistance. If it's below the price, we call it Support.
The meaning, if we go by pure theory, it would be too much. Let's keep it short.
Resistance, to translate it simply in Price Action or price terms, it resists
and prevents it from going up. Simple. It's like a wall.
It's like a barrier. When price comes up and hits it, there's resistance.
Or a price wall. As for Support, the meaning is literal.
It supports and prevents it from going down. That's the concept. Resistance prevents upward movement.
If Support means it supports and prevents downward movement. Now, how do we create Support
and Resistance levels? Look at Swing Points.
The term Swing Point means it goes up then goes down.
If it's in the middle of price movement like this, we won't use it.
Use where it reverses.
Because it means it must have hit something, couldn't continue
and had to go in the other direction. Right?
Like these, it hits then continues on.
We won't use these as Support or Resistance. When it can't continue and bounces back
hits and bounces back, we'll use these. Like this, can't continue, reverses down. Comes down, can't
continue, reverses up. Every Swing Point like this, we'll use as Support or Resistance.
If it's above, it definitely resists upward movement. Above must be Resistance.
Below, it supports and prevents downward movement, so it must be Support.
And as I said from the start, count it as a zone, not drawing a single line as a price.
Support and Resistance, according to their meaning, is resisting and preventing downward movement.
This means Resistance often has price reversals
when it's been rising, rising, rising
and when it hits, it reverses down.
Support is the same.
It keeps dropping, dropping, dropping down.
When it hits Support, it supports and prevents downward movement.
According to the concept's name.
Support, it means there's a chance
let's use the word "chance." There's a chance it will reverse upward.
Away from the original direction that was coming down to hit Support.
As for Resistance, away from the original direction that was coming up to hit Resistance
which is the opposite direction, which is down.
There's usually a price reversal by
reading it together with candlesticks.
See? Pinbar.
Pinbar going down, right? Down.
This one's a group, but if you combine them, it becomes a Pinbar too.
In the principle of combining candlesticks that we learned in the earlier Parts.
Therefore, Support and Resistance, we'll use them together with candlesticks that show buying or selling pressure.
If the candlesticks we know, that we learned in the candlestick Part
if we encounter them in the middle of the chart, they won't really produce results according to their names, like reversal candlesticks and such.
Candlesticks will have clear effects only when they're found in areas that are Support or Resistance zones. Only then will they clearly produce those expected results.
Which case? Like coming down and encountering a candle like this. This isn't a Pinbar. Where is it?
And if it's not in a Support or Resistance zone, like this
Pinbar shows buying pressure returning. Dropping, dropping, dropping, but why doesn't it reverse back up like this?
Because it's in the middle of a trend. It's not in a Support or Resistance area.
Like this, see? When it's here, it goes up.
See? It produces clearer effects. Simply put.
Another concept of Support and Resistance you need to know is
originally, if it's above like this, price moves up and hits it.
Coming from below up to hit above, that's called Resistance. Right?
But whenever Resistance is broken through upward, when price breaks through upward
it immediately switches from Resistance, its role changes, to become Support.
From originally resisting upward movement, preventing upward movement
when it breaks through, simply put, the resistance couldn't hold, it broke.
Breaks up. When it reverses back down
what used to be Resistance will change to become Support, supporting and preventing downward movement.
In the same level, same zone.
Comes down. Retest, simply put, comes down to test.
Resisted upward movement, got broken through, damaged.
Therefore, it's no longer Resistance because it's below the price.
It becomes Support, according to its name. Supports and prevents downward movement.
So it becomes a reversal point to continue.
It will change its role. Like this one is Support.
Supports preventing downward movement, bounces up. Supports preventing downward movement, bounces up.
Finally, it gets destroyed. From Support it becomes Resistance.
Price comes back up to retest, comes up to hit again.
So originally it supported preventing downward movement.
When it's damaged and broken, it means it got broken through downward.
It will change its role to become Resistance preventing upward movement.
Come here. Understand the concept and remember it.
Then it drops.
Here, this is Support.
This breaks down. Support changes to Resistance.
Comes up to hit, and the same point that used to be Support before
now resists preventing upward movement, then drops.
Down. This is the role of Support and Resistance.
Like in this picture, it's also Support and Resistance.
But it's like the trend we've been seeing.
It's a trend.
This might be a clearer trend.
Going up step by step like stairs.
Hits, then hits and drops.
This is Support, bounces up.
Goes and breaks through, right? Breaks through, then hits a new barrier, which might have existed before.
It drops. When it comes down here, what was this? It was Resistance, got broken through, switches its role to become Support, supports preventing downward movement.
It continues up. This one used to resist, couldn't hold, got broken through. Reverses down, it supports preventing downward movement.
Changes role. Breaks through again, goes up to hit Resistance, comes down to hit Support, that's how its steps continue like this.
And the principle for drawing good Support and Resistance is to start from the larger timeframe down.
Like this will be a weekly timeframe, a weekly chart, weekly graph, this is Resistance.
See? It's a major level. Go ahead and draw it. It's a zone, a Support zone.
When it zooms down to daily, if it moves up and hits here, and forms a reversal candlestick pattern
like this, it's around this area that belongs to
a larger timeframe. Therefore, it will be thick, solid, as a
strong Resistance. Using the word "strong," how many points?
Count them. One, two, three, four, five. The word "strong" means there's
it's been hit multiple times already, whether Support or Resistance.
Using the term hit multiple times, price has hit and crashed into it.
But couldn't break through. If it's Resistance, couldn't break up.
If it's Support, couldn't break down.
That shows the level is even stronger.
This is why it drops so much, so far, after hitting Resistance.
Let's look at a real chart for a bit. A real chart. Look at the points.
This head, draw it like this. This is horizontal.
Our horizontal lines, we're talking about horizontal, so draw them.
This is drawing from what we see. But if we do it properly, know the history first.
Suppose I'm comfortable trading the 1-hour timeframe.
I'll take the larger one to control first, which is 4-hour.
This is the point where it swung, came down then reversed up forming a tail showing returning strength.
Then go back to the past. See? There's this point where it came down and went up.
Here it hit and went up. This shows this level works. So we draw it for the 4-hour.
Where else? Like here it has bounces. This is interesting. See?
Comes up, hits and drops. What role did it play, remember?
It was Resistance, resisted upward movement. Finally the Resistance broke, broke through.
Reverses back. What is it now? From Resistance it changed to Support.
Supports preventing downward movement. Can't go down, so it goes up. See?
But there's another thing I mentioned, don't forget.
We don't look at it as a single line.
Not taking this price, a single price. It's not this price that is Support or Resistance.
We take it as a zone. Like this, if you draw it as a zone
it becomes clearer like this. See?
This, it touches the zone, touches the zone, touches the zone a bit.
And finally it stays. And comes down touching the zone.
Resistance is here, this zone. You can combine them all this way, combine them all.
Like this. It hits and drops, hits and drops, hits and drops. See?
So we mark it like this. After marking on the larger timeframe
we'll break it down to smaller timeframes, well, smaller ones
and mark what we just saw. Look at the left side.
This is our left side. Here's where the current price is running on the chart.
So we look back at the past.
The points where it clearly bounced up. Here.
We mark and set them up.
If the line is above the price, that means it's Resistance.
Therefore, if price breaks through this Resistance upward
Breaks through. Price runs, boom, breaks up.
Where will it go next? It'll be clear, right? There's nothing blocking it anymore.
Price will keep running until it hits the next Resistance.
The next level.
When price goes up and hits it, we need to watch at that moment to see if price
will hit and pass through, or if it doesn't pass then
it'll reverse down. Look at the candlesticks.
Reverses back down. Look, this is the old Resistance.
Already broken through. It becomes Support. Comes down to test Support.
Right here. Boom.
Comes to test if it holds.
Right. It holds.
It holds. If it holds, price returns.
Goes back up.
If there's a lot of buying pressure, it might break through this Resistance.
Could break out. Break out like this, could go far.
If it breaks, where will it go? To the next Resistance. Right here.
Goes and hits it. Resistance does its job resisting upward movement. Then it'll curve down again.
It'll reverse downward again. It'll keep going like this.
Understand now? Support and Resistance in horizontal form.
You mark where you see repeated points.
Like three or so. For example, when I mark here, did I mark this correctly?
We haven't seen what's behind yet. Based on what we see now, it should hit this line.
This is Support, comes down and bounces, comes down and bounces up, breaks through, breaks through, comes back. This level must become Resistance, right?
And it comes up here. It resists down, resists down, resists down. Finally
it breaks down. All the way here. Reached this major Support zone.
Very clear Support. When it hits, see? It holds and prevents it from dropping.
It holds and bounces up like this. See? Now if it can break through
Boom, breaks down. Down. It reverses back up and hits this zone.
This Resistance zone. Originally it was Support. Already broken.
Change its name. It becomes Resistance. It resists, prevents upward movement. So it drops.
Price drops. Hits there and drops out. Here. Now if we try to look back
Let me look back. Here, here, here, here, here. See? Hit here again. This zone again.
This zone again. See? Hits and drops. Comes down and hits. Here and goes up. Bounces, bounces, bounces.
Until it's able to break through. Here it reverses up to hit again. Here. See? Here.
About this much is good enough. Looks like it broke through a bit, but couldn't continue.
So it drops like this. Still counts because like I said, Support and Resistance aren't viewed as a single price line.
It's a Price Zone. Like this. Like this. See?
Here. Here. We didn't know before. We don't know what's behind. We mark what we see now.
Based on current data, these 3 points didn't break. Mark here first.
Here too. Right. Once we mark it, it misses. After it misses, we look back to see if this level is really strong.
It all checks out. This is a zone, see? It doesn't reach exactly, but remember it's a zone.
It's a Price Zone. So it drops like this.
Therefore, this line should be fairly strong.
Therefore, if price, or here, comes up to hit here
we analyze or consider the trend
that there's a chance it won't break on the first try.
Might reverse back first.
Come to form new patterns, then go up.
This is the point where we'll consider buying or selling pressure
to see who wins, who dominates more, from what we learned about
about reading candlesticks. We look at it together with
this right here. We'll see a clearer picture than when we first
learned about candlesticks. We read them candle by candle.
Like before, we read by going up, until we reach here. Reading here, it's strong. Selling pressure is strong. Probably won't hold.
Reading down, up, up, down, and so on. Reading continuously, there was no, basically no focal point.
There might be a percentage that makes our reading and analysis of candlesticks
or buying/selling pressure or Momentum
less accurate. But if combined with Support and Resistance
it's a level we already know that it must play an important role where
price must do something in these zones.
If we compare it to
like comparing to the candlestick lessons we learned, Momentum as a battlefield
there are 2 cities fighting each other, to seize territory
who can enter whose territory more
Support and Resistance are like city walls or checkpoint walls.
So when it's a checkpoint wall, that means the wall must have who?
Must have soldiers guarding, obstacles blocking, right?
So we need to look at the forces battling there to see if they can destroy the wall.
This side, the city on this side, if it's an uptrend going up to hit Resistance, we need to see if
the army attacking, coming to assault, does it have strong or weak forces?
Is it at full strength or is it weakening? Against the army waiting to defend on the wall
at this level that already exists. Will this side be able to resist?
Can they push the enemy back? We'll know step by step.
Instead of reading candlesticks continuously from what we learned about Momentum
which already gives us information as a story
if we understand from the previous lessons, from previous parts
we can already read Momentum and candlesticks as a continuous story.
When we combine it with Support and Resistance as zones
it tells us exactly which points we should focus our reading on more.
Instead of reading through dozens of candles, which might be confusing
information might be wrong or inaccurate. But if we already know the positions we need to focus on
we just read buying or selling pressure at the moments when there are Support and Resistance
positions like these instead. It'll save us more time.
But if you want the overall picture or want to analyze more deeply
we read like we read before
from previous lessons, read through the entire set, read continuously
but at points where you encounter Support and Resistance, analyze more specifically
whether it will go or not go.
Because if it goes, it must go to the next level. Each level basically tells us, besides preventing upward movement
like I said before, this is the city wall. If the forces attack and break through
the next wall is here. Now you ask, what happens in this zone?
It doesn't do much. The troops just keep advancing
to attack the next wall or next city. That's it, to seize the new city and keep attacking forward.
If we compare it to warfare, it's exactly like this. It's normal.
In the function of Support like this, it holds price from dropping
so if it drops through, it broke this wall already, so it must go attack the next city wall which is the next zone.
Send the soldiers. When soldiers reach the next wall zone
the troops from this side send forces to fight, to fight and reclaim the territory back.
That's why they defend to prevent us from entering their territory too.
Hit, hit, hit, down, down
So we analyze like this.
If it drops, where does it go?
If the forces from below try to push up and lose
they'll retreat as normal. If we go fight
and we lose, or we can't fight anymore, we're exhausted
where do we have to go?
We have to return to our base, return to our army camp.
The question is, if we fight here and can't hold, we must return to Support level where it was before
like we go back, go rest first. It already won here before, we're defending here
right? This is considered their city wall. But fighting here doesn't work anymore.
When the army advances this big, like a wall appears, it protects the zone.
Taking that zone becomes the zone they're holding, according to the size of their candle.
When price hits and can't break through, encountered this level before, they retreat back.
See this huge candle? Remember?
If suddenly there are small candles and then a big candle appears from the start
that's it, the trend will go in the big candle's direction for a while. So see? When it comes, it goes this way again.
It sends forces this way again. Like it can't fight back, right? So it keeps sending the same army here.
They move the army, move the army here, attack, attack inward, attack until the defending forces can't hold anymore.
Keep going continuously.
See? It's like in this area, after breaking through for a while
in this area they have new forces forming a wall right here.
How did this happen? If you look back at this line, this line
See here? It bounces back.
This is this zone. Hit then drop, struggling here, hit
This one
This shows they still have military forces waiting
waiting to fight. That's why it must bounce. The army is coming. Simply put, they might be tired from traveling.
Momentum starts decreasing, the big candles start getting smaller and smaller and smaller.
Trying their best to push but in the end might start weakening.
Then small green candles gradually creep up, and finally defeat this army.
See? Price manages to close above this one. So keep fighting. Fight to where?
Fight back to where they just crossed over the city wall here.
This first checkpoint wall. Come here, then go back up to reclaim it.
Make it ours again, so the enemy doesn't reclaim it.
Hit then drop, hit then drop, hit then drop, trying to reclaim it.
Still can't reclaim it yet of course, because here it's still considered in the period of
sideways. Still fighting each other on this level. Here might be winning a bit
then shifts to the next Resistance level, which is here. Still fighting.
It's just the strength of Momentum, candlesticks, like we've read before
it'll make analysis easier, clearer, increase your trading percentage even more.
Let's continue watching.
Next up is Dynamic Support and Resistance, or the sloped type.
Earlier, Support and Resistance were horizontal, right? Now the sloped type, how is it? It's trendlines basically.
Let me open a new one, let's say this one works.
Let's continue.
This one I like Fuji.
We can look at this one.
At first, this one already went like this.
See, it's a zone?
The horizontal one.
Bouncing for a long period because if you know
it switches roles, from Support to Resistance.
Goes up, hits, drops. See?
Now we move to the horizontal type, we already know that.
Let's do the sloped type, the one with slope like this.
Draw like this.
If it's a downtrend, we'll draw from the peak downward like this.
Then create a channel to make it parallel, let it run like this.
You'll see it becomes Support and Resistance in diagonal form like this.
It's on top, it's a downtrend. So along this line
it must be Resistance.
Below, when it's below it becomes Support.
When price comes to hit the lower line it becomes Support.
This one first, Support like this.
Here, right here
Around here, see?
When we draw trendlines, we'll draw two clear points first.
Use this as point one.
Point two, take a nearby point, nearby peak.
This one might be a bit off, skip it.
We take this point and this point, these two points, then let the rest run.
For this we create a parallel channel at points it passed through before.
The top will be Resistance. Price runs down, reverses back up.
Sometimes price reverses back and forth, we might not see on the horizontal axis
why it bounces. Like here it might be struggling, not clear.
Why does it drop? But actually here there's a little bit.
Around here. They're fighting. Try looking back, is there anything? It's still not clear.
Actually we can kind of see it in another technique which we'll cover later, which is Fibo.
It happens to drop and retrace to around 55%, then it drops. But today we'll talk about it later.
But since it already happened, we take the point where it occurred, this swing
and this swing, connect them together and extend it out.
It becomes a channel. Make the bottom parallel to be Support.
We have Resistance already, now we'll have Support.
That's why when price runs to hit Support or the diagonal line, it goes up.
Hits, goes up, hits, hits. Goes down, down, down, down, down, down, hits again, then goes up. See?
Because if we want to know, wait, what's on the horizontal level that makes it go up?
It has to go up here. We can try observing this line.
This line, this line, horizontal. Oh okay, because when it reverses back below, there's still a point where it must bounce.
And it also has this line, so we can consider this one quite strong because there are 2 overlapping lines.
Two stories, two types of Support and Resistance switching roles.
Switching roles. In an uptrend, is there an uptrend? Yeah, uptrend first.
This one here, then we take this point, this Low.
The clear one would be like this one.
Let's zoom in a bit more.
Want to make it clearer.
Draw a channel there.
The bottom will become Support.
At this point we'll take it as point 2.
So we don't know if it's Support yet.
We have to wait for this formation to happen first, then we can draw it like this.
Once we draw it like this, it means we've got the top.
So the top has to become Resistance, right?
So when price runs from this point up,
pretty strong momentum too, runs up strongly, and this green candle,
this long and big, boom! Hits Resistance.
Still can't break through. That's why it curves down.
Ah! Tests again, still can't break through.
This one's like the final strike, boom!
But you see,
if we read by Momentum and candlesticks,
it shows there's selling pressure, an Engulfing back.
The other side won't let it go through, simply put.
So it reverses back because it's a Resistance zone.
Same thing, even though it's diagonal, we can still count it as a zone.
Take the closing prices and the shadows, we can draw it.
So it reverses back into the Channel.
Like this.
Then it comes down here, tests.
Tests Support, bounces up.
Goes up, comes back down to test again.
Down here, tests, bounces, tests.
See? It keeps testing Support.
This shows the diagonal line we drew
is acting as Support.
When price hits it, it bounces.
But look at this area,
when it breaks below Support,
this Support line
will switch to become Resistance.
See? Once it breaks below,
it tests from below, can't break through.
Tests again, can't break through.
This means the diagonal line switched roles
from Support to Resistance.
Same concept as horizontal Support/Resistance,
just on a diagonal.
So whether it's horizontal or diagonal,
Support and Resistance can switch roles.
This is what we call dynamic Support and Resistance.
Because it has a slope, it's not flat.
It moves with the trend.
That's why we call it dynamic.
Alright, so this is trendlines and channels.
Very useful for drawing Support and Resistance
that moves with price.
Now let's look at
another tool, which is
Fibonacci.
Fibonacci, or Fibo for short,
is a tool we use to find
Support and Resistance zones too.
But it's based on percentages
of the price movement.
The key levels are
23.6%, 38.2%, 50%,
61.8%, and 78.6%.
The most important is 61.8%,
also called the Golden Ratio.
We use Fibo to measure
where price might pull back to.
Let me show you how.
In an uptrend,
we draw from Low to High.
Like this swing here,
from this Low
to this High.
Then when price pulls back,
we watch those Fibo levels
to see where it might bounce.
If it bounces at 38.2% or 50%,
that's a shallow pullback.
If it goes to 61.8%,
that's a deeper pullback.
If it breaks 61.8%,
the trend might be weakening.
In a downtrend, we do the opposite.
Draw from High to Low.
Then watch for Resistance when it bounces.
Let's see an example.
Here's an uptrend.
We draw Fibo from Low to High.
Click the Fibo tool,
click at the Low,
drag to the High.
There, we get the levels.
Now watch when price pulls back,
where does it bounce?
Look, it bounces right at 50%.
like this tail
they allow you to draw it like this
you can draw the trendline because this is a swing point, see? Price came down then went up
came down and went up
so you're allowed to draw and test it, because it's like
it's a scare candle, reversed back down...
went up, there's still no closing price that went beyond this line downward
this is what we call discretionary, acceptable
something like this is acceptable
looks like it'll break through the trendline upward
but it didn't actually break
see, it wicked up
then reversed back down
so this is considered
acceptable, within discretion
But if it clearly breaks through
like breaking way up here
then coming back down
that wouldn't count anymore
understand?
So this is
the trendline concept
Drawing trendlines is about
finding swing points
When you connect swing points
you get a trendline
Once you have a trendline, you can
use it to analyze price movement
Like we'll wait for price to test this line
when it comes to test
if it bounces, we can trade it
or wait for it to break through
if it breaks, we trade the breakout
That's how we use trendlines
Next, let's look at
channels
Channels are drawn by
taking the trendline concept
and adding a parallel line
Like when we have an uptrend
we draw the trendline at the bottom
connecting swing lows
Then we draw a parallel line
at the swing highs
This creates a channel
Price moves within this channel
bouncing between the upper and lower lines
When we see a channel like this
we can trade it
Buy at the lower line
sell at the upper line
or wait for a breakout
If price breaks above the channel
that's a bullish breakout
If it breaks below
that's a bearish breakout
Let's look at an example
Here's a clear uptrend channel
See how price
keeps bouncing between the lines
touches the bottom line
bounces up
goes to the top line
bounces down
This creates a trading range
within the channel
We can use this to plan our trades
When price comes to the bottom
we look for buy signals
When it reaches the top
we look for sell signals
or take profit
Now let's see
a downtrend channel
In a downtrend
we draw the trendline at the top
connecting swing highs
Then add a parallel line
at the swing lows
Price moves down within this channel
Same concept, just inverted
We can sell at the top line
buy back at the bottom line
or wait for a breakout
The key thing about channels is
they help us see
the range price is moving in
and plan our entries and exits
Now an important point
about drawing channels
Sometimes you'll see
the channel isn't perfect
Price might wick outside
but not close outside
That's still okay
We use discretion here too
As long as the closes
stay within the channel
we can still consider it valid
Just like with trendlines
If we explain the theory in detail, it'd be really long
It's one of the
technical tools
that acts as psychological Support
It has specific ratios
The important ones are these
38.2%, 50%, and 61.8%
So when price moves up
If it pulls back, there are 3 lines
where price has a chance to bounce as Support or Resistance levels from Fibo
So let's say price moves up like this
When it pulls back
It might bounce at 38.2%
or 50%
or 61.8%
These are considered
psychological levels
that traders pay attention to
It's like
when price reaches these Fibonacci levels
traders will watch to see if it'll bounce or break through
But this is just a tool
We still need to combine it with other things we've learned
like candlestick patterns
price structure
to confirm
whether it'll really bounce at that level or not
Alright, so Fibonacci
is one popular tool
that many traders use
Okay, next
We'll talk about Trendlines
Trendlines
are lines we draw
to connect price swing points
For an uptrend
we connect the lows
the bottom points
When we draw a line connecting them
it becomes an uptrend line
For a downtrend
we connect the highs
the top points
When price comes to test this line
it often bounces
So the trendline acts as Support or Resistance
For example, if we draw an uptrend line
Each time price pulls back to touch this line
it tends to bounce up
If it breaks through this trendline
it signals that the trend might be changing
might be weakening
So trendlines
are very important tools
for identifying trend direction
and finding entry points
Okay, next we have Channels
Channels
are when we draw parallel lines
both top and bottom
The bottom line is Support
The top line is Resistance
Price will oscillate
bounce between these two lines
When it hits the bottom, it bounces up
When it hits the top, it bounces down
This is called trading in a channel
If price breaks out of the channel
either breaking the top resistance
or breaking the bottom support
it signals a potential trend change
or strong momentum in that direction
So channels
are great for range trading
buying at support, selling at resistance
Alright, these are the basic tools
for finding Support and Resistance
Whether it's horizontal levels
Fibonacci retracement
Trendlines
or Channels
They all serve the same purpose
helping us find where price might
bounce or reverse
But remember
these aren't 100% accurate
Sometimes price breaks through
Sometimes it bounces
We need to combine them with
candlestick patterns
price structure
and other confirmations
to make better trading decisions
Don't rely on just one tool
Use multiple confirmations
That'll increase our probability of success
Okay, now let's look at
some real chart examples
so you can see how these work in practice
Here we can see
This is a clear uptrend
Price keeps making higher highs
and higher lows
If we draw a trendline
connecting these lows
You'll see price respects this line
Each pullback touches the trendline and bounces
This shows the trend is still strong
But look here
When price breaks below the trendline
it signals trend weakness
After the break, price starts moving sideways
or even reverses
So trendline breaks
are important signals to watch
Here's another example
This is a channel
Price is bouncing between
the upper resistance line
and the lower support line
Each time it touches the bottom, it bounces up
Each time it touches the top, it bounces down
Very clear pattern
If we trade this channel
we'd buy near the bottom support
and sell near the top resistance
But watch what happens here
Price breaks above the channel
That's a breakout signal
After breaking out, price continues moving strongly upward
This is why channel breakouts
are important trading opportunities
Now let's look at Fibonacci
Here price made a strong move up
Then it started pulling back
If we draw Fibonacci from the low to the high
We can see the retracement levels
Look here, price pulled back
and bounced right at the 61.8% level
This is a common Fibo level
where price often finds support
After bouncing at 61.8%
price continued moving up
resuming the uptrend
This shows how Fibonacci levels
can help us find good entry points
during pullbacks in a trend
Alright, so these are practical examples
of how to use these tools
Now you can practice finding these patterns
can't break through, meaning it can't push higher
So here we might think, well, it might not make it
Maybe it'll drop back down first? Let's wait and see? Or what?
But we see another candlestick trying to break through
Alright, so when it breaks through, we see the role switches
from what was Resistance, now acting as Support
See? When it breaks through, the role reverses
supporting from below
Then it bounces up again
continuing the upward move
Alright, so this shows how Support and Resistance
can switch roles
This concept is very important
for understanding price movement
Now let's look at another example
This one combines multiple concepts
Here we have a trendline
which is diagonal Support
The price keeps testing this line
bouncing up each time
This shows the trendline is strong
because it's been tested multiple times
Now look what happens when it breaks
The trendline switches from Support
to become Resistance
See how the price tries to go back up
but gets rejected at the old trendline
This is a perfect example of role reversal
The same line that was supporting
is now resisting
Alright, let's talk about channels
A channel has two parallel lines
The lower line is Support
The upper line is Resistance
The price moves between these two lines
bouncing from Support to Resistance
and back down again
This is called channel trading
When the price is at the bottom
touching Support, we can buy
When it reaches the top
touching Resistance, we can sell
This works as long as the channel holds
But what happens if it breaks out?
If it breaks above the upper line
that Resistance becomes Support
The same role reversal concept
we've been talking about
Now, there's one more thing
about Support and Resistance zones
Remember, we don't draw them as single lines
We draw them as zones or areas
Because the price doesn't respect exact levels
It moves in zones
So when you're drawing Support and Resistance
don't try to be too precise
Draw zones instead
This gives you more flexibility
and better accuracy
Alright, let's look at some practical examples
on real charts
Here's a chart showing horizontal Support
You can see the price bouncing multiple times
from this zone
Each bounce makes the Support stronger
because more traders recognize it
Now look at this Resistance zone
The price tries to break through
but gets pushed back down
several times
This shows the Resistance is strong
Until finally, it breaks through
with a strong bullish candlestick
Now watch what happens next
The price pulls back
to retest the old Resistance
which is now acting as Support
This is a classic retest pattern
and a great trading opportunity
If you see a Pinbar here
at the old Resistance turned Support
that's a high-probability setup
combining candlestick patterns with Support and Resistance
This is what we call confluence
when multiple signals line up
Alright, so to summarize
Support and Resistance are price zones
not exact lines
They can switch roles when broken
Support becomes Resistance
Resistance becomes Support
The more times a level is tested
the stronger it becomes
We can use them with candlestick patterns
for better trading decisions
Support and Resistance work on all timeframes
from 1-minute charts to monthly charts
The concept is the same
just on different scales
Now, when you're analyzing charts
start with higher timeframes first
like weekly or 4-hour charts
to find the major Support and Resistance zones
Then drill down to lower timeframes
to find your entry points
This top-down approach
gives you better perspective
of the overall market structure
Alright, we've covered a lot today
about Support and Resistance
This is Part 2 of Price Action
In Part 1, we learned about candlesticks
Now in Part 2, we've learned Support and Resistance
These two components together
form the foundation of Price Action trading
When you combine candlestick patterns
with Support and Resistance zones
you'll have a powerful trading system
The key is to practice
looking at many charts
identifying these levels
and watching how price reacts
Over time, you'll develop
an eye for these patterns
and you'll start recognizing them quickly
Remember, Support and Resistance
are the most important tools in Price Action
and when you find these simple patterns, that's it
there's consistent profit opportunity
Thank you very much. Goodbye.