Hello everyone, welcome to the Forex Pre-Action course.
We'll read candlesticks like reading a story - understanding the meaning behind the price action.
Let's just get started right away - we'll cut straight to the point, no fluff.
But for those who already have a basic understanding of candlesticks,
what they mean and how to read them, you can skip ahead to the next lesson.
This is for complete beginners who don't yet understand candlestick charts,
what they look like, what they mean, and how to read them.
This lesson will be the absolute basics.
Let's start with charts.
With Price Action, we look at charts like this second one here.
What I mean by "naked" chart is,
we'll still use some tools,
like drawing lines here and there to help with the analysis.
But we won't be using
lots of stuff like this.
We won't use tons of indicators. Some traders who have their own system
are comfortable with this approach.
They look at where indicators cross, which points
are interesting for selling or buying.
But for Price Action traders, they prefer analysis that's
clean like this - nice and clear.
Price Action consists of three main components.
At minimum - there could be more depending on each trader's specific techniques.
But at minimum, anyone using Price Action will use these three things.
First is Candlestick analysis. Next is Support and Resistance levels.
Resistance and Support, and the last one is Dow Theory.
This is really important - Dow Theory, trends, and market direction.
Now let's get to know candlesticks.
For those who don't know or are still new to this.
Actually, when we configure candlesticks in our platform,
we can set them to any color we want.
Here, I'll use green to represent bullish candles - upward movement.
"Bullish" means the price keeps moving up - buy low, sell high.
Red candles mean the price is dropping - bearish movement, for selling.
From this image, you can see the opening price is here, and when the candle closes, the price has moved from here up continuously.
It might drop first to make a low point, then move up to make a high point, and then close.
Simply put - a bullish green candle means the close price is higher than the open price.
For red candles, the close is lower than the open - meaning the price dropped.
The price keeps dropping, pulling back. Green means the price keeps rising.
Keeps going up. Now, if you see candles like this,
with no wicks sticking out, no tails - it still has the same four price components.
It's just that the open price overlaps with another price - the open IS the low of this candle.
And the close price IS also the high of this candle.
Vice versa - same thing for this one.
The high price is the open price of this candle.
Then it got pushed down by selling pressure until it closed here.
This becomes the low point where it closed.
It closed at the same level as that price.
So no matter if the candle has a tail, has wicks, or no wicks,
it must always have these four prices.
Now these are some other variations you might see.
We've already covered this shape.
Like this one - it still has four prices.
Opens here, then moves up or down, but when the candle closes,
it comes back and closes at the same level as the open - that's why it looks like just a single line.
But there are actually two prices overlapping - the open and close prices.
It reached this low point, and the open and close are together here.
That's why the prices are overlapping.
Here's a simple explanation of price movement.
If it opens here and has a wick below, that means the price must have gone lower than the open.
So it might have opened, dropped down, then moved back up.
Until it reaches this high point then falls back to close a bit, or it could open and go straight up to make the high, then drop all the way to the low, and climb back up to close around here - not higher than this, so it stays at this level.
These two candles look the same, but the actual price movement was different - see that?
So the simple conclusion is - a candle can move in any way.
You just need to know that it must always have these four prices to form a candlestick.
You should understand now - no matter what kind of candle it is, like this one,
opens here, moves around somehow - drops to here then bounces back up,
or it could go up first, reach this point, and close here.
When it closes here, time's up and a new candle starts - the prices must connect like this.
Let me show you another example - this is really for beginners so you can visualize it better.
Let's say the opening price comes in - opens right here.
Then the price moves around - maybe like this during the hour, keeps moving like this.
Drops to here, slowly climbs up, drops again, climbs back up, finally reaches here.
Then it might zigzag around this area, or it could fall - but when the candle's about to close,
say it climbs up to here - here we'll get the components.
Four components - what are they? The high price - this is the highest price.
The open price is here, the lowest price it reached is
here. When the candle forms, it becomes a candle
shaped like this - see? Open, close, and the parts sticking out are the wicks.
That's all there is to it. So it doesn't have to move in any specific pattern.
It can move however it wants - any pattern is possible.
But in the end, it must always create these four price points.
We'll always know exactly where the open is and where the close is,
and the highest point it reached and the lowest point it reached.
These all combine to form one candle.
This is candlesticks for those who are new to trading,
so you understand what candlesticks mean and why they have these different shapes.
To summarize simply - if the close is lower than the open, it's a red candle, a bearish candle.
If the close is higher than the open, it's a green candle, a bullish candle.
It's that simple. The shape of the candle depends on how the price moved during that candle's timeframe.
Now we come to candle size.
This is a large candle, this is a small candle - small body.
Why does it matter? Why do we need to know about large and small candles?
It tells us which one has more strength.
Like this candle - if it's a red bearish candle,
talking about selling pressure - between this candle and this candle,
it shows the strength in a direction or which side has more control over the other side.
In a case like this,
it's red -
we already know that sellers have more strength than buyers.
Read candlesticks like reading a story - understand the meaning behind them.
Let's just get started - we'll cut straight to the point, no fluff.
But just a quick note - for those who already understand the basics of candlesticks,
what they mean and how to read them - you can skip to the next lesson.
This is really basic stuff for absolute beginners - those who don't yet understand candlestick charts,
what they look like, what they mean, how to read them - that kind of thing.
This will be the most basic content in this lesson.
Let's start with charts.
With Price Action, we look at charts like this second one here.
It's a clean chart like this - when I say "clean",
we actually do use some tools,
here and there - like drawing lines to help with analysis.
But we won't use
this kind of setup -
tons of indicators. Some traders who have their own systems
already developed - they're comfortable with this approach.
They look at where things cross, which points are
interesting spots to sell or buy - something like that.
But for Price Action traders, they prefer analysis that's
clean like this - nice and clear.
Price Action consists of three main components.
At minimum - there could be more depending on each trader's specific techniques.
But at minimum, anyone using Price Action will use these three things.
First is Candlestick analysis. Next is Support and Resistance levels.
Resistance and Support, and the last one is Dow Theory.
This is really important - Dow Theory, trends, and market direction.
Now let's get to know candlesticks.
For those who don't know or are still new to this.
Candlesticks - when we set them up,
we can set them to any color we want in the program.
Here, I'll use green to represent bullish candlesticks.
"Bullish" means the price keeps moving up - buy low, sell high.
Something like that. Red candles mean price going down - bearish, for selling.
From this diagram, you'll see the open price is here, the close price is when the candle forms - price runs from here and keeps going up.
It might drop first, come down to this point to make the low, then run up to make the high, and then close.
Simple summary - bullish candle, green candle, means close price is higher than open price.
Red candles - open is higher than close, meaning price is falling.
Price is decreasing, pulling back. Green means price is increasing.
Keeps increasing. Now, if you see a candle like this,
with no wicks sticking out, no tails - it still has the same four components.
It's just that the open price overlaps with another price - the open IS the low of this candle.
And the close price IS the high of this candle.
Vice versa for this one - same thing.
The high is the open price of this candle.
Then it gets pushed down by selling pressure until it closes here.
This becomes the low of the candle where it closed.
It closes at the same level as that price.
So no matter what - whether the candle has tails, wicks, or no wicks,
it always consists of these four prices.
Now, this section shows other patterns that can form.
We've covered this one already - we learned this pattern.
Like this one - it still has to have four prices.
Opens here, then runs up - or down - but ultimately when the candle closes,
it comes back to close at the same level as the open - that's why it's just one line like this.
But there are two prices overlapping - the open and close price.
It runs to this low, with open and close together at this level.
That's why the prices overlap.
Price movement - this is the simple version.
Opens here, and if there's a wick below, that means price had to go lower than the open.
It might open, drop down, then run back up.
Reaches the high here then falls back to close - or it might open and shoot straight up to the high, then drop all the way to the low, then back up to close around here, not higher than this point.
These two candles look the same but their price movements are different, see?
So in simple terms, one candlestick - it can move however it wants.
You just need to know it always has these four prices to form the candlestick.
You should understand by now - no matter what kind of candle, like this one,
opens here, moves somehow - it drops to this point then reverses up.
Or it might go up first, reach this point, then close here.
When it closes here, time's up - a new candle forms, and prices connect like this.
Let me show you another example - this is for complete beginners, you'll see it more clearly.
Let's say the open price comes in - open price, opens right here.
Then price moves - who knows how - maybe it moves like this for 1 hour, keeps going like this.
Then down to here, then gradually up and up, drops again then up and up, climbs to this point.
Then might bounce around this area, or maybe drop back down - but when the candle's about to close,
say it comes up to here - at this point you'll have the four
components - what are they? The high price - this is the high. The
open - the open price is here. The low price that it reached is
here. When the candle forms, it becomes a candle
like this, see? Open, close, the part sticking out is the wick.
That's all. So it doesn't have to move this exact way.
It can move however - anything's possible, any pattern.
But ultimately, it always creates those four price points.
We'll definitely know where the open and close are.
And the highest point it reached and the lowest point it reached.
These combine to form one candle.
This is candlesticks for those who are new to trading.
Now you know what candlesticks mean, why they have these different shapes.
Simple summary - if close is lower than open, it's a red candle, bearish candle.
If close is higher than open, it's a green candle, bullish candle.
That's it - simple. The shape of the candle depends on how price moved during that candle's timeframe.
Now we get to candle size.
This is a large candle, this is a small candle - small body.
Why is it important? Why do we need to know large vs small candles?
It tells us which candle has more strength.
Like this candle - if it's red, a bearish candle,
we're talking about selling pressure - between this candle and this one.
It indicates the momentum in that direction, or which side has more control over the other.
In a case like this,
it's red -
we already know sellers have more strength than buyers.
That's why it's red.
But it doesn't have as much pushing power as a large candle.
That can push it down this much - this is how we look at momentum.
We'll go into more detail about this in the next lesson.
About price momentum.
That's important for reading charts - reading them like a story.
Like a map, like a narrative. Now, which candles
are considered large? We know this one - we can see candles large and small.
But when candles actually appear in real trading, they come in groups like this.
Which ones are called large? Which are called small?
To determine this, you need to look at context.
The whole group of candles in that area.
If in that group you have candles like this,
small, small, small, small - then this one pops up,
this one's called large.
But if in their group they're all mixed together,
boom boom boom boom -
it's not called large.
They're about the same - this is called
the same group.
This is large. This isn't called large -
significantly large.
This one's called large.
See?
But let's say in a group like this,
you see this candle - this still isn't called large.
They're similar - similar sizes.
These are small, small, small - see this one? That's large.
Got it?
Can you visualize it?
What about other groups?
Earlier we saw a candle like this - called large.
Let's say you see both of them around the same area like this.
This, this, this, this, this, this - these four candles, five candles, six candles -
they're considered similar, not called large yet.
They're in the same group.
The large one is this one - this is called large.
This one could also be called large.
Because it stands out a bit.
But in terms of momentum, they're still similar if you count the wicks.
Still considered similar - this one doesn't stand out yet.
This one is truly large.
This part we'll learn together later.
Let's look first - from the beginning, these small candles we saw, their shape -
there's also this shape - all wick with a small body left.
These are reversal types - this one's a single candle, this one comes in sets.
Like this one, here, and here - this is a set. This pair indicates reversal, they have their own names.
Like Engulfing, this one's Railroad or double track - Western names, depends what you call them.
Here's Pinbar, a Doji, this one's railroad from above, this is Engulfing from above.
The meaning is price moves - this is Bullish Candlesticks, means it's reversing to bullish.
About to reverse to bullish. Can you picture it?
I'll go through this quickly because we haven't reached the key points we need to learn yet.
Like price moves this way - it's in a downtrend, keeps dropping.
When you see this candle - boom - there's a chance, I say there's a chance it will rise.
Other sets are the same - chance of rising.
If you see reversal candles. This one's Bullish Candlesticks -
means it's been going up, then sees this one break in - chance of reversing to bearish.
All of them are similar, but we won't memorize them like this.
We won't memorize patterns - like "see this one, it must do that."
It fails quite often if you approach it this way.
Meaning it doesn't work - it might not go up or down according to theory.
Or as they say.
Why? Let's take a look.
Here we go - various candlestick patterns.
There are tons of them - this type is a single candle. Look at single candles first - just one that supposedly signals reversal. Now let's look at examples, see?
Here, Doji - something like this around here.
These are supposed to mean reversal.
But when you see them, do they reverse?
Maybe a little bit.
In Pin Bar,
Shooting Star -
this one, this bearish candle like this -
should go down. But it doesn't drop, it keeps going up.
If we try to sell around here,
see this candle and sell -
looks like it'll work, like it drops a bit, but then it goes back up.
See? Well, that means it's not accurate, not right.
See it here, and here again.