Alright, let's jump into Reversal Candlestick - this is a special episode, folks.
Yeah, this one's gonna be focused on reversal candlesticks.
Now, those of you who've been following from the beginning know what's up.
If you're new here, let me fill you in a bit.
Basically, this whole series came from one simple question.
Students were asking, "What's the difference between Season 1 and Season 2?"
What are we actually learning here?
So I thought, alright, let me break it down for you guys.
Season 1, right? That was all about the basics.
What we call Foundation, the fundamentals.
Look, there are tons of different indicators out there.
Some folks swear by RSI, others love MACD.
You know what I mean?
So many different tools, and yeah, people use all kinds of stuff.
Everyone's got their own preferred tools.
Now, in this course - and I gotta be clear about this.
I'm not telling you this is the ONLY way to trade.
What I'm teaching you is Price Action.
That's our approach, Price Action.
Price Action means we're reading and analyzing just the price movement itself.
Basically looking at candlestick charts and understanding what they're telling us.
And here's the thing - Season 1 had two main parts.
First part was Dow Theory.
Now Dow Theory's got six principles.
Actually, some people say there are more.
And yeah, I might've covered a bit extra beyond the main six.
But anyway, there were six core principles.
You gotta understand those, right?
And after Dow Theory?
We dove into candlesticks.
And look, when it comes to candlesticks, there are SO many different types and patterns.
I mean, seriously, tons of them.
You could spend forever trying to memorize every single candlestick pattern out there.
But honestly? I'm not gonna make you memorize all that stuff.
We're gonna keep it simple and practical.
I'll just show you - "Hey, when you see THIS pattern, here's what it means."
Basically teaching you what each pattern is telling us, what it's saying about the market.
And it's not just about recognizing patterns - we need to understand WHY they work.
Get the logic behind it, you know?
That way you're not just seeing random shapes - you actually GET what's happening in the market.
So what does "complementary" mean here?
Alright, let me explain - sometimes you'll see charts that look different, various patterns, right?
You might see this pattern, or you might not see that one.
But here's the thing - if you spot these together, whether it's from Season 1 OR Season 2.
The more clues you stack up, the stronger your conviction becomes.
It really reinforces your forecast - makes it way more likely to play out.
Yeah, it's gonna follow through just like you predicted.
So now, what are we gonna talk about in this one?
Action and Reaction - that's today's topic.
I know some of you are wondering, "What's Action and Reaction?"
Think of it like forces, you know? Action force.
Action and Reaction forces.
Reaction is basically the force that pushes back in the opposite direction.
Imagine a ping pong ball, or a soccer ball - whatever works for you.
You kick it, throw it - it hits the ground.
That impact force? That's what we call the Action.
The ground responds by pushing force back.
That's what makes the ball bounce back up like that.
Makes sense?
So the ball comes down, and right here is the impact point.
And it bounces right back.
That's the easiest way to explain it.
Or you could just call it resistance force.
Imagine if this was a wall.
Yeah.
A car crashes into it - BOOM! Right? The force of the car coming from this side, all that energy coming this way, and then...
What happens to the front of the car? It gets crushed, wrecked. There's a反force coming back.
It's not just one-way force - it doesn't just pass through or anything like that.
It's not like the car stays perfectly fine, crashes through the wall and keeps going untouched.
No way! The car gets damaged, right? That's the reaction force at work.
Same thing happens with candlesticks, folks.
Exactly the same principle with price movement.
So the Action is basically the price running in this direction.
But normally with candlesticks...
From Season 1, we were looking for THIS pattern.
But you can't always find it, right? That's why we have what's called...
Combined candlesticks. Could be multiple candles - two, three, four, who knows.
But when you add and subtract all the movement together.
Boom! It forms a candlestick pattern.
Like this, which I already explained back in Season 1.
It represents the反force pushing back - that's one type of pattern.
Price was running down this way, and when you combine all those candlesticks together...
You get this formation - buying pressure bouncing back up.
If it's coming from a downtrend, right? Coming from downward movement.
When it's coming down - boom, boom, boom - we see candlesticks forming in a cluster.
They bunch up together, not appearing cleanly like this all at once.
But when you combine them, you get this formation.
That wick, right? What it's showing us...
That's the Reaction happening.
Bouncing back from that Action side.
Trying to push price back in the other direction.
The opposite side.
But it doesn't always work out that way.
Sometimes we see a clean pattern like this before candlesticks even combine.
And we think, "Oh yeah, it's gonna go this way."
But no way!
It comes down.
Gets to this point.
And keeps going down.
Because all the elements aren't there yet.
I already covered this back in Season 1.
What elements make this pattern work best?
Don't forget - each candlestick we learned in Season 1 is like a character, showing different character types.
What makes a character perform their best? Or what they call having the clearest action? That's the SCENE.
What's a scene? Where should it occur? If you don't remember, go back and review our lessons.
Let's move on. So here's how it works, folks.
Action and Reaction - let's say this left side here is the Action.
This side is Action, and then Reaction comes down - there's a反force pushing back.
I'm talking about the downtrend side because it's easier to see. On the flip side, we have the uptrend.
Price moves up, then reverses back down - same concept.
But when talking about this side, price looks like it's moving up like this, and this side becomes the Reaction.
Let me give you a simple visual - think of a balance scale.
A balance scale with arms on both sides like this.
Simply put, it's measuring forces.
The force on this side has to be selling pressure.
While this side has to be buying pressure pushing back.
But talking about selling pressure and buying pressure gets confusing.
Right now, if we discuss this, you might get confused - wanna know why?
Because over here, it's a downtrend - selling pressure is the Action.
Buying pressure pushing back is the Reaction - it's reversed because we're on the upper side.
Yeah, price runs up, hits resistance - boom! Reverses.
Earlier on this side, it was selling pressure - we still call it that.
Buying pressure becomes the opposite, because it's on this side.
It becomes buying pressure - we call it buying pressure.
And selling pressure becomes the other side. Confusing, right? Going back and forth gets messy.
So from now on, I'm just gonna use TWO words.
That's Action and Reaction.
And they stay on the same side consistently.
Doesn't matter if it's top or bottom.
Going up? That's Action.
This one's the Reaction.
This side coming down? That's Action.
Going up is Reaction.
It just becomes left side versus right side, that's all.
Alright?
This side - the left - is ALL Action. This side - the right - is ALL Reaction.
Keep it simple. It's gonna look like this - this is the pattern we're looking for.
Back in Season 1, we might've only needed this much. But now we want MORE confirmation.
Stay tuned for the next episode.