Now we've reached the next topic, the next episode, which is about Sideways markets.
Normally price goes up like this, then it consolidates like this, then continues, then changes to go down.
The cycle will be something like this.
Before this, we already learned about reversals.
Those points there are reversal points.
Now we're going to learn about Sideways, this period here.
During Sideways, will it go up? Or from Sideways will it go down?
It can change either way.
It's not that if it's Sideways and it's in an uptrend, it must continue up. It could go down too.
Now let's look at how we analyze candlesticks, the conditions of the balance scale.
The price balance scale, Action and Reaction, how does it work?
Let me erase this first.
Now let's look at the easy analysis of Action Reaction in Sideways markets.
Before this, here was an uptrend coming up like this, which we already looked at.
This part is different, it's a different chart from yesterday.
Now we're going to look at the part where it went up and then consolidated Sideways. What happens next after Sideways?
Let's take a look.
Right now I've drawn the support level approximately at these points here, understanding that support is an area.
It's an area, not a single thin line.
Not a single line like this, support can't be like that.
It has to be an area, a range.
Check here, it held and didn't go down. Here it was resisted.
So this is an area that has density or is like a wall of price that blocks it.
Or it's like a barrier, as we've learned, that it can't pass through yet.
Because once it passes through, it will continue like this.
Now let's say we don't know about this part yet, that it's going to be Sideways.
Let's look. Now we'll get the axis.
The balance scale axis, here it is.
The balance scale axis is here.
Now what else are we going to look at?
We get the highest price point here, closed at this point.
Then we look at the left side and right side, which is Action and Reaction.
We have the center axis now, right?
The center axis of the balance scale, remember?
From the previous lessons, we need to have the center axis first.
Then we can measure the force, like this.
On this side that's bearish, we get this one.
Draw it here. Does this side exceed half?
Half would be about here.
So this exceeds half of the axis.
So does this candle count? Yes, it counts. And is it a lot? Yes, a lot.
See how it won going up like this?
So after we see this, it means price has a chance to consolidate, which means pull back down because it's quite strong.
It went way beyond, a lot.
Now if we look at it with Momentum from Season 1, see? It had force pushing up to here then contracted back down.
Ending like this.
This is selling pressure, selling pressure pushing down.
Very clear, the red side.
This candle got hit down, getting ready to reverse.
And the next candle opened and followed down again like this.
This is the highest point, so we'll count this one.
Actually we count this one. Whatever happens, we don't care about other price points.
And then swing up again. This one is the axis. Let's look again and adjust the line.
Here, the axis is here.
This is Action, this is Reaction.
Very close, but it looks like Reaction loses slightly.
So price can't go lower than this yet.
It consolidates further, see? It can't win all at once.
This set compared to this set has less, I mean the force is decreasing.
Reaction is decreasing. So this much isn't enough yet.
It can't finish going down in one go. This one is even less.
And we need to find the next one, the highest one of the later group that swung up after Sideways.
Which one is it? There are many. If finding the highest, it's this one.
This line, and stick it at the boundary like before, at the Body.
And find the Action Reaction sides. This is Action, see? Right here.
Does this side have more? Has more, this one. Still small.
Force is still small, not enough yet. Resistance first. See?
This side, evenly matched. So can it go down?
Not down yet. Price went up here, came down, still not down.
Up again, up again.
Let's find it. These 3, which one is highest? This one.
It's this one, then adjust here again. It'll be at its Body.
About here.
So which Action do we get that exceeds half?
Exceeds half. Zoom in and look.
Here, here.
See this?
This one exceeds half. Exceeds half, count from the Body.
Don't count this one. This one, see how it exceeds half?
Here, count placing right here to fit perfectly, perfectly.
Exceeds half here. So count this.
As Action on this side. This side is about here.
And Reaction? This doesn't exceed, see? Doesn't.
Here, does it? This is about half, this one. Does it have force yet?
Does this have force? No, no force, no force. This one has force again.
See? To push it down. So price ended up running down.
Remember that if it gets it, we have to keep counting.
Here, it will run like this. See? Like what we've been doing.
Look, this Low here, it went up here, right? What we just counted is still Low.
And went up here. This is Sideways, see? It's Sideways for a while.
And do you see anything? That the old Low is here, and here the Reaction force, this one.
This one wins, so it must be lower than this Low, right? Must be lower. See?
In the end it came down lower like this.
This one got it slightly.
See? In the end it broke lower. Won this much.
It doesn't say here wins, then after Sideways it will win this one.
Or come to this one. You have to gradually look step by step.
Like this, now this is the latest Low. It will win the latest Low, then come down.
Then up again. If you see this as a level already.
It becomes resistance, see?
And slide over like this.
But now we need to look at its force too.
We've been looking at the force here for a long time.
For a long time, this is the very first point where price ran up and we said it must.
Here it already told us that price must win this point, so we won't.
Come look at this to find if it must win here. That's a different matter.
This one has to win the Low in its own Sideways section, in its own group.
Which is its Low, which is this one here.
This is the latest Low. If it wins, it's this one.
But this one already said it must come down anyway.
So it's the long-term picture that this one tells. It just might not happen at this time immediately.
But this Sideways, in the end it will have a story.
See? It will have a story at each point saying whether it succeeds or not, going on and on.
Until it meets a point where it succeeds.
Measure at this one. Action, put the line here like this.
Run up. This is Action. Came down.
Action is about here. Which side is Reaction?
Does this exceed? This one should exceed.
We'll count this one. Does it become having force? Does it have force?
No force. Which means it shouldn't pass this.
See? It shouldn't pass. But in the end it did pass.
In the end it passed. We already talked about what happens.
Something that shouldn't happen, like it shouldn't be possible, but it becomes possible.
In the end there must be a reversal of something.
Suppose it shouldn't pass, should go down, but it doesn't go down, it continues up.
That's it. It will come back down lower than now immediately.
There will be a swing like this, upward swing.
So downward swing is the same. It comes back to swing like this.
Simply put, if it's a downtrend, what must it be like?
Must be, um, should go down already, but it comes back up instead, then it becomes like this.
Here, shouldn't pass, but it passed, so in the end it reverses and hits back up.
Wins violently, abnormally. Abnormal like this.
Becomes a candle like this, higher than this already.
So this one becomes, it's like this one ran up.
Swing here, swing. Swing down, swing up.
So which one do we count? We come back to count this one again, like this.
See? Find the line down. This side, now there's nothing on Action side.
No green at all in this Zone. It would have to go far to find this one.
Which we won't use, right? We don't count going back that far.
Let's take just about this much. But Reaction came down this much.
So it already wins. If going to break, it already exceeds anyway.
It already must break the old Low here anyway.
Because just this much already exceeds.
Price swings swings along. In the end it came down.
And this one already said from the start it must reach this one, at least.
In the end price came down to here. See?
This Low here. If we take, if we take this one, take this one out.
See? It reached here, which is lower. See?
That here is lower than here. It will be from this one, this set that told us.
Price came down to here. Now look at this.
And do you think it will go up here again?
Will it be like swing down then swing up, uptrend here?
We have to look again. It's not that it went down, hey, wait here.
But actually we got the picture from here already.
Because it must come down about here, which, ah, here actually it already reached.
This exceeded already too, maybe. Ah, exceeded, see the tail exceeded.
The tail exceeded already. The tail of this one truly reached here already.
The result of this one, it reached the tail of this one already.
Now once it reached, what happened? It's exactly at support.
This one, as soon as price came down, it immediately bounced back up.
It might come back up like this. Right?
It came down to support. The price came down, came to test support from what passed before.
Test. And might reverse back up again.
Because here the job was completed successfully already.
The candlestick set, the balance scale that said here, that the Action and, reached here already.
A lot. So there's no way it will go up to this High for sure.
It just goes up up up up. In the end got slapped down because it can't go.
If reading Momentum it already loses, this set was already losing.
It's selling pressure already. This, one, two, three, selling pressure.
Here. Actually it's a line here. It's selling pressure already.
In Season 2 style reading the future ahead, you already see that it can't go either.
So everything confirms each other, showing that we're confident we won't trade against it.
Here it will become a downtrend like this. We don't dare to buy against going up.
Because it can't go far.
See? It has, uh, the force here. It came down, it swung came, pa pa pa pa pa.
To here, this is the lowest. Then it came to receive, swing came like this.
This is Sideways. It's in a frame.
If you look, see? Here here here, it's on the downtrend leg like this.
Here, Sideways like this, right?
It's just this thick. Let's see, what? Ah, this is green, this one.
This side is definitely this one, as Action.
And then this has to be this one. This one. See?
At first it was this one. Now it's like this, feels like even worse than before.
Like the force is decreasing even more.
Can't fight, just barely win. The previous High is definitely this one.
Price has no way to come up to this one. Count this one as Action.
This one is Reaction. The force isn't enough.
So when it bounced up here, it can't reach here.
It might come up to about here first.
If it will win here, we already learned that it must do, do what?
Something like this, which is make, refresh the force like this.
Here the force isn't enough for it to go up to win here.
It might have to wait another bit where here there's more force.
Win here and go up, like this.
Then chase up like this again. Which is have to look at Action Reaction points.
Chase step by step up to where it will be able to win.
Here it doesn't win in the near future.
Came up, scroll down to see. It's here right?
Swing up then down. Wait, will there be a higher point than this?
Found a point higher than this, because this point is, it swung like this, might come to this point.
Right? Is there a higher one? Going forward it chased up already.
So now not this point, it must come up to about here.
So it will be this shape. Like price came down like this.
Not quite lined up. We have to come here. Like take this, and come here.
The swing will be like this. So now we'll look.
Suppose it's a swing, erase this first. This one.
The axis comes to here. This is here. This can be used.
So this one has force. It will chase up. Have force.
Then will win this. Because this one if receiving the original.
The area around here, it already won. This is the latest one.
It might be this one. Go up to this, this one. Will it go down?
Scroll and see. Showing that it still goes up.
Not finished yet. Follow it first. Follow it.
Now count this as the axis. Because it went up to here.
Because it hasn't won this one yet, but already won here successfully.
Now here. We'll look again at how far down it will go.
Does it have force to go down? Here is the axis.
This definitely counts. Does this exceed half? About half.
About half. Wait for confirmation. Doesn't have, so this one is half.
Actually it's half. So maybe count this one.
Asking if there's force down? If suppose we count this one, it loses.
Here is the axis. Here. Loses. I mean here.
Here. Loses. So will it be able to come down to this Low or this one?
Not likely that it will go down. So it might go up again.
Wait because it, it doesn't have force to press down to reach this area.
See? It just chases up and this, will it go down? It just slaps slaps slaps up again.
Becomes new. This one went up, down up. So it will become, change to count this one.
Now let's look at this one. Not this one. This one must be the axis.
This one must be the axis. As a new axis. But because after this one ran and came here.
And went up here. This one will become the axis. This one, stick at the axis.
Stick the line. Stick it. Then we find what? Uh, Action Reaction. Get which one?
This one doesn't get it. This one gets it right away. This one gets it.
Here. Make this one clear. Once this one gets it.
We'll see that between this one and this one, this one has more force.
And when comparing sets, compare sets.
Between this one and this set. This set has less force. This set switches sides.
Like the balance scale changed. It changed, showing force increased.
So it will have more force to go down than before. But this one didn't go down much.
It bounced back up to make swing number one. While it's Sideways.
This has a chance to come down. Come down further. Force is quite a lot more.
Because this one is very small. Came back down a lot. If reading.
Reading about bringing Momentum in, or energy in, or measuring force. Got it.
There's a chance to come down more than before. More than before.
And bring other things in as well. Support and resistance.
Forgot that we already learned from theory. It's not that we look at only one thing.
The balance scale, you must look at where it happens. The components must be complete.
Remember? Now where will it be complete? Here. Is it an important level?
Is it resistance? It's resistance. And it's a trendline here.
Very likely, not likely, it's an important position already. It's an important scene.
If we read cartoon style, it's an important scene already. The cast is complete.
It switched from less force to come up, has less force. Can't go down yet.
But came to resistance area, the same. So this time it comes, it still won't go down yet.
It goes on. Close to each other already. Around the resistance area like this.
That day there's a chance to come down. Normally from Price Action, it also...
This resistance. If it's Sideways down, right? It must come.
Next receive is receive here. Or receive at the horizontal level.
Whichever. Now we'll look. Gradually came down. Because its force is more, see?
Here is the swing of bouncing back. Will it bounce back past this resistance?
Hey, will it bounce back? Wow. Like about half a bit.
This one definitely gets this candle as Action. We, Reaction must be this one.
Wait. Finished this. Here. Do you see? Action Reaction.
Will it go lower than this? Went down first. Can't go down.
In the end this one has more influence. Because this one can't overturn or break through.
It went up like this, that's it, won this High. This old High that's bigger that covered from the start.
BREAK this out. See? This is how we read it.
Should understand more now. Should understand more about the method of reading.
About this. The method of reading is like this. That is.
Read Sideways, read when reversing we already read. This is reading during the way.
Sideways, whether it will continue or Sideways then slap down.
If here it shows signals slap down. If suppose this candle Action Reaction is like this.
Price also has a chance to slap down. But it's not, because it shows that.
It goes the same direction, you see? This says pass. This says don't pass.
Which is this says up, up a lot. This says down little. Correct. It tells correctly.
But if this says up a lot, this says down a lot. Hey, they contradict each other.
See? Clear signals contradict each other. But this one doesn't contradict.
It goes the same direction. This says up. This says down little.
It does come down a little bit, around the sides. And around this level area.
Anyone would have a chance to see it as sell down. Because this is all resistance.
See? Resistance of the trendline. Resistance of the line. Resistance here.
And got a long pinbar coming down closing red like this too.
And Sideways on the side. Slowing down like this.
Momentum going up very little. If looking as Momentum, small small short candles.
Anyone would look sell, slap down. But Action Reaction says it should go up.
It becomes like this. So we understand. About this.
Should be able to apply and use now. Like special episode.
Special image. This special image ends at this episode like this.
Ends at about this much. Which is got more tricks. If calling it tricks.
Additional tricks that you can bring to use in trading next.
Practice. Which is practice then collect experience.
See that normally the candles we see. Candle candle candle candle like this.
There are many things hidden inside. Did you ever notice and look for them and find them?
That's all. Whoever got to the end, congratulations.
Considered that just your learning just this much is, came out, whoever didn't come out.
But learned all 3 ways already. You must go back and review.
It's up to you. You'll get additional weapons here. See?
This. And even more, whoever got to learn young news too.
Congratulations, you almost have everything complete. Others they also see the chart, candles like this.
But they don't see like this. See what's hidden. But you see.
Bring it to apply. Everyone good luck.
Move back to the original first. At this one. This one bounced up here. Where did this bounce down? Is there lower? This one is lower.
Then move here. See? Move here. The axis follows like this.
We get Action on this side. Action. As for Reaction, this one is balanced.
This green might not get it yet. Ah, really doesn't get it. Doesn't have. Oh have, have, have.
Have this one. See? This one. It closed like, this thin one. Move a bit.
A bit. Here. But it closed like this. This place it closed. It exceeds this one.
See? In the end it went down. Came down here.
Came down then bounced up. So around this area. And which one is it?
You find which one is lowest. Which looking already it should be.
All very close. Probably the green one.
Take the green one. Here. Action. Reaction. Find it now.
Which one? See. Exceed half or not? If exceed half, count.
Balanced. If exceed half or not? Count.
But it's balanced. You're not sure, then consider the force evenly matched.
Suppose count just these two. Consider very evenly matched.
But if count next one. Let's see. Don't clear this one.
Suppose doesn't exceed half, must count this candle green. This one not clear.
Must count this candle. Evenly matched anyway.
Or here actually exceeds half already. Can't count this candle. Must count this candle. Loses.
Loses. Must do balance again. Wait for them to do balance first.
They go up up. See? When they go up, they still haven't won the old swing.
Uh, old High. Because here the force says isn't enough.
Close to evenly matched. If count here with here, which is evenly matched.
Move up a bit, still doesn't get it. Here if it bounces down.
We'll count this one down. Um, down bounced swing came like this.
Look at Action and Reaction again. But suppose it wins.
Suppose it goes up, it wins. What abnormal will happen?
It will fall down violently anyway. This one doesn't exceed half.
This candle doesn't count. And must count Action this one.
Air Action see already. This one. Loses or not? Loses. Force enough to come down to win this one or not?
Not enough. So it still won't go down. It has no way to be lower than.
Whether opportunity better, not really. Not really. Means no way.
Opportunity for it to be lower than here is small.
Comparing to old Low, Low ahead is small. So shouldn't be lower than this.
So can it bounce down? Bounce down. This must bounce down for sure.
Because here it, it went down. But Reaction it loses. Action.
It might come down to about here. Scroll scroll go. But still no higher.
So it's this swing for sure. Might come down to here.
Go up here. See? It still hasn't come down to win here.
This. Because this one won. This is, uh, this is.
Here see? The balance scale tilts like this. This won. Still wins. Wins.
I mean not reached. See? Not reached. Still not reached.
But asking why it went down. Uh, earlier we didn't look.
It swung to here. And swung up, highest of this one, which one.
Which is this red one. That one then moved like this.
Wow. Got it. This green. This one doesn't get it. This one doesn't get it. This one gets it.
This. This is Action. This is Action already, this one.
This Action. Which is the other Reaction? This doesn't exceed.
It's very balanced, this one. Come draw line right here.
So the green one floats exceeds up. The float floats lower down than here.
Count this one. This one hard. Scroll come this then still doesn't exceed half.
That day count this one. Dark a lot. More a lot.
Then won the old Low which is this Low. Which is this short short Low just this much.
Not this Low. That. Just this Low just that much. Then won, came down.
So this one bounced back up. Swing then changed.
Swing changed like this. Like this. Got it. This lump.
This candle got it. It will be, uh, be like, this one. Have or not?
This still doesn't have at all. Still doesn't have any increase.
We must scroll until find the one that got it. This. Exceed half.
Body exceed half. But it's close, evenly matched.
So should, continue. Still not won this one. Which is, this High like.
No lower than this, we then move to count here.
So it swung up already. And came down here, count here.
Adjust come down. This. Red. This still not half.
This still not half. See. Came over not to half. Can't count this candle.
After this doesn't have. That exceeds half it will have just this one. This.
Which is far. Sometimes we won't count. We'll consider this side doesn't have Reaction already.
Come look green side. This one got it, see? Dark at this, here.
The Action balance scale other side here, but this side doesn't have. Doesn't have Action.
But have Reaction. So price has tendency. From this swing.
That will climb up higher than this High. Higher than this High.
Then going along. Wow. Higher or not? Oops. Dud dud dud. Still not reached.
Go down or not? Still not down. Uh, Sideways continue.
Actually almost count this one already. Uh, wait for confirmation candle.
Then use something to confirm continuously. Oh wait for swing.
Wow. Actually it's, this. Went up and came down.
But it's considered this is all Sideways set. It still doesn't look like clear waves yet.
See? Here. Then go. Go. Ah, went down already. Ah, still not won. See?
This High is still lower. Uh, came down. But this one says have force.
It should go up. Hmm. It bounced down.
But it shouldn't be lower than this already. Because this one has force.
It still doesn't have anything that would say to slap down lower than this.
The set above here already. Uh, wait see if it will bounce or not.
Uh, this. Here. Low is here. Doesn't go lower. This. Still not reached. See?
But this already went up. So I'll change this set to here.
Then here is the balance scale axis. The axis is here.
This one exceeds or not? Exceeds half. Exceeds. Exceeds already. Clear, this exceeds half for sure.
This red one. Green. Exceeds or not? Exceeds half or not?
Exceeds already. You see force exceeds what up. Action Reaction Action High.
The old is here. Latest High. And this one.
But you see the force is different. Compare this set with this set.
Or this set that became swing before. See? This loses, can't go up to exceed this.
This doesn't have force. This one. Here. Count here. Count here.
Green here. Close. Uh, in summary. Less force. Less force and it has a lot of force here.
So what must happen? Less less lot. Remember head and shoulder at all?
Less, so it doesn't pass. Less doesn't pass. Finally third time lot, then broke through up.
So there's tendency that price. Sideways is. If draw frame it will be like, similar to triangle like this.
See? Low raise higher. Higher. Have chance Break triangle up to upper side this side.
Go up after it consolidated for a while. This one we can enter buy.
Then if going let it run long up. It won. High this for sure.
From past already it broke triangle. If this one is triangle really.
We look at Pattern, it must continue at least.
About the distance of about here. At least must have about this distance.
But it only came to here, the lowest point, then it didn't come down to lower zone.
Half of the downward leg. It also has a chance already. In Momentum it also says will raise up.
This reads one way. Um, bring to enhance, this, see? Then I also read Momentum go.
But it's not reading Momentum how. Then I'll see already.
Set this. Set this. Set this. Until at this set.
And the force of this set increased. So there's a chance price will jump up.
Also high at this point already. Um, came to see. Went up. Um, see?
It must win High first. Which it also won successfully already. From this point.
Have force. This is what happened. Do you see the traces of price or not?
That it tells us. Not that it doesn't tell us at all. It tells very clearly.
You just need to find the traces to find them. If you read Momentum.
Some you read Momentum may be from short one candle.
Um um um um um um um um um um um um um um um um um um um um um um um um um.
Here here here this is resistance. And broke through the resistance, see?
Anyone would look down. At this time. Um, must come down to line. This. Must come down.
Maybe come to trendline below this? Or come resistance here.
But we read what? Earlier we read what? Action Reaction helps.
Um, the part here it says it must pass. Must go up. Force increased.
Suppose it met this one again. Hey, measure. You measure.
Hey, this one. This is the axis. Here. So you'll get this one.
Here is Action for sure. Exceed half already. This. This Action.
And Reaction. Must be this one. Wait. Finished this. This. See?
Action Reaction. Will it go lower than this? Went down first. Can't go down.
In the end this one has more influence. Because this one can't overturn or break through.
It went up like this, that's it. Won this High. This old High that's bigger that covered from the start.
BREAK this out. See? This is how we read it.
Should understand more now. Should understand more about the method of reading.
About this. The method of reading is like this. That is.
Read Sideways, read when reversing we already read. This is reading during the way.
Sideways, whether it will continue or Sideways then slap down.
If here it shows signals slap down. If suppose this candle Action Reaction is like this.
Price also has a chance to slap down. But it's not, because it shows that.
It goes the same direction, you see? This says pass. This says don't pass.
Which is this says up, up a lot. This says down little. Correct. It tells correctly.
But if this says up a lot, this says down a lot. Hey, they contradict each other.
See? Clear signals contradict each other. But this one doesn't contradict.
It goes the same direction. This says up. This says down little.
It does come down a little bit, around the sides. And around this level area.
Anyone would have a chance to see it as sell down. Because this is all resistance.
See? Resistance of the trendline. Resistance of the line. Resistance here.
And got a long pinbar coming down closing red like this too.
And Sideways on the side. Slowing down like this.
Momentum going up very little. If looking as Momentum, small small short candles.
Anyone would look sell, slap down. But Action Reaction says it should go up.
It becomes like this. So we understand. About this.
Should be able to apply and use now. Like special episode.
Special image. This special image ends at this episode like this.
Ends at about this much. Which is got more tricks. If calling it tricks.
Additional tricks that you can bring to use in trading next.
Practice. Which is practice then collect experience.
See that normally the candles we see. Candle candle candle candle like this.
There are many things hidden inside. Did you ever notice and look for them and find them?
That's all. Whoever got to the end, congratulations.
Considered that just your learning just this much is, came out.
Whoever didn't come out but learned all 3 ways already.
You must go back and review. It's up to you.
You'll get additional weapons here. See? This.
And even more, whoever got to learn Season 2 too.
Congratulations, you almost have everything complete.
Others they also see the chart, candles like this.
But they don't see like this. See what's hidden. But you see.
Bring it to apply. Everyone good luck.
About this. The method of reading is like this. Like read Sideways.
Read when reversing we already read. This is reading during the way, Sideways, whether it will continue or.
Sideways then slap down. If here it shows signals slap down. If suppose this candle Action Reaction is like this.
Price also has a chance to slap down. But it's not, because it shows that it goes the same direction.
This says pass. This says don't pass. Which is this says up, up a lot. This says down little. Correct.
It tells correctly. But if this says up a lot, this says down a lot. Hey, they contradict each other.
See? Clear signals contradict each other. But this one doesn't contradict.
It goes the same direction. This says up. This says down little.
It does come down a little bit, around the sides. And around this level area.
Anyone would have a chance to see it as sell down. Because this is all resistance.
See? Resistance of the trendline. Resistance of the line. Resistance here.
And got a long pinbar coming down closing red like this too.
And Sideways on the side. Slowing down like this.
Momentum going up very little. If looking as Momentum, small small short candles.
Anyone would look sell, slap down. But Action Reaction says it should go up.
It becomes like this. So we understand now. About this.
Should be able to apply and use. Like this special episode.
Special demonstration. This special episode ends here.
Ends about this much. Got more techniques. If calling them techniques.
Additional techniques that you can bring to use in trading next.
Practice. Practice and collect experience.
See that normally the candles we see. Candle candle candle like this.
There are many things hidden inside. Did you ever notice and look for them?
That's all. Whoever watched to the end, congratulations.
Considered that your learning just this much already came out.
Whoever didn't come out but learned all 3 ways already.
You must go back and review. It's up to you.
You'll get additional tools here. See? This.
And even more, whoever learned Season 2 too.
Congratulations, you almost have the complete set.
Others also see the chart, the candles like this.
But they don't see like this. See what's hidden. But you see.
Bring it to apply and use. Everyone good luck.