Let's continue with this episode. Action and Reaction are our main focus in this section.
Now, you guys get the overall picture, right? But we're gonna expand on it - there are more details to cover.
So far we've just understood that there's Action, and Reaction on this side. This one absorbs the energy.
It gets absorbed and released. Candlesticks and various momentum converge at this point.
Reaching a strong, important support level and key zone. Then there's aåforce pushing back.
That becomes the Reaction - causing the direction that was moving to reverse.
Now there's more detail than this. Let's look at this diagram. See this? In reality, in the price cycle...
Everything references Dow Theory. The biggest theory. I'll tell you straight - when you learn what comes next, Dow is the foundation.
If you see a chart like this - say you don't see this half yet - or people who learned Season 2, they can predict ahead automatically what direction price will go next.
Totally automatic. Super easy - just glance at it. But this one's gonna fill in the gaps for those who already learned Season 2.
Let's look at the price cycle - it looks like this. This is called 1 cycle - going up until down, or down until up, then back up again.
Basically an uptrend - going up continuously until it can't go higher. Like hitting a wall. What happens? It starts from Low - what's this? High.
You lift the Low, right? So it becomes Higher Low, Higher High, Higher Low.
Higher High, Higher Low - but then it doesn't make a new High. See? No more Higher High. Instead it starts making Lower Low and Lower High.
Another Lower Low, another Lower High. And so on - the cycle looks like this. Uptrend then downtrend. Uptrend, downtrend. Now in these, what else is there? Hold on.
We've already learned this. Let's get to what we don't know yet - this one.
These are candlesticks - we know there are 3 patterns. It's measuring the power of both sides - Action and Reaction.
So what does it consist of? What's it made of?
Normally when price goes up, right?
It doesn't just go up like this straight. Does it? While going up, it has to have ups...
And pullbacks, ups and pullbacks, ups and pullbacks - like this.
During the pullbacks, it might just pullback normally and continue up.
Or during this pullback zone, it could go sideways.
At this point what forms? If it's a workshop rain pattern, it becomes a double top.
Right? Hits the top, comes down. Comes down and bounces.
During the downtrend, we say it comes down and bounces up - bounces to continue down.
Consolidating. Consolidating like this. Consolidates then breaks through, continues down.
Bounces, can't continue down - hits strong support.
Reverses back up. And cycles like this continuously. The price cycle looks like this. Let me erase a bit. Yeah, this works.
Now these candlesticks - Action, Reaction, or Passion candlesticks - combine 3 candles. One, two, three - there are 3 patterns. See?
Each pattern appears in different locations.
Like this - let me review first what we call them.
What do we call them, right? Better if I change colors.
Blue then. Yeah, this one's normal, see?
Balanced means they're roughly equal. Because Action equals Reaction.
See how the forces are evenly matched? Look at the body on this one.
Remember we look at the body? This one.
What's happening with this one? Action and Reaction.
Action is stronger - this one. Reaction is weaker. See?
Reaction can't fight - can't beat Action.
It's lower. It can't beat it.
Can't beat Action - this candlestick. So it comes out looking like this.
As for another pattern - Action is weaker, or Action...
Wait, Reaction is stronger. Yeah, see how it comes out like this? With all the components...
Complete. It exceeds half of the body.
When it goes up, it'll gradually rise like this if it's this pattern.
The balanced one. If it's this one though - it goes up without strength.
Not much power going up like this. See? It's weak.
Reaction normally responds to the opposite side. Price comes down, bounces up just a tiny bit like this.
Shows it has little power. "Little" means...
It might not pass the previous High. The previous High - the direction won't pass the previous High.
The most recent High. I'm using "most recent High."
But if it exceeds - it looks like this.
It's strong. There's a chance the price bouncing back as Reaction...
Can beat the previous one. See? Yeah, goes up like this.
So the chart pattern or formation that should appear at different points...
This one is where? Right here. Goes up, consolidates.
Yeah, it doesn't have much strength, so it can't continue yet.
Just consolidates. After that, goes up again. Yeah, goes up again, then meets the other side.
Don't forget it has to be on both sides - not just one side.
On this side. Yeah, this side comes down, causing a pullback upward.
This has to beat the original High. Here it forms a new High.
Following Dow Theory, right? This is a High.
It has to make Higher Highs continuously. So this one has to be characterized by strong upward movement - the power has to be strong. See how strong it is?
It beats this candlestick. So it pushes price up to make a new High.
Finally, when it goes up, it hits strong resistance.
Comes down and won't go back up. Now it hits this one - see?
What happens? Which side wins? Action, Reaction wins.
So it makes a Low that's lower than the previous Low. See?
Becomes a Lower Low from the previous Low here.
Beats the previous Low going down because it's strong. Yeah, then continues down.
Here there's hesitation - goes sideways. Consolidating.
But we can say it's a price consolidation period. Then comes down again. Yeah, bounces up.
Hits this set - see? What happens? Action, Reaction - stronger force.
Can break through. Makes a new Low. Gets a Lower Low.
Consolidates here, then goes back up.
The price cycle looks like this.
We use this to see if there's strong or weak power to beat...
The previous High or previous Low.
Using the word "beat" - I mean if it's like this...
It won't pass the most recent High if it's trying to go up.
If it's on this side, might only go up this much. Down - both this one and this one.
But if it's this one, there's a chance it'll beat the previous High.
If we say starting from here, it has to beat this High. Not this High.
Using "most recent High" - it'll beat that. But if it's this High and starts from here...
There's a chance it'll beat it and make a new High.
After going up doesn't mean it'll keep going up forever.
It might pull back then continue.
Or drop down completely.
But definitely has more power or more chance than normal.
Let's use "more than normal."
That it'll beat the most recent High.
Or the most recent Low if it's a downtrend.
For the one that has strong power like this.
Goes up like this.
Getting it? I'll explain in more detail.
Because it doesn't end here.
There are other patterns too.
To help understand.
Fresh page. It'll look like this.
Now we already know when price goes up...
This one's just called a normal pullback.
But normally price has zigzags - zigzag pattern all the way through.
Kind of odd-shaped like this.
Could gradually go up again.
Or even go up like this, then come down.
And here - a candlestick set like this.
Where the power isn't enough to beat this High - might only go up this much.
Then down again. Then comes to form a new one here.
A stronger candlestick pattern. Then breaks the High.
Could be in two sections like this. Let me expand on this.
Because what patterns are there? Actually there are many, many.
Yeah, first one is sideways. What kind of sideways? Yeah, price comes up like this.
Yeah, then continues.
It has to be - yeah - triangle formation like this.
See? Now where do the candlesticks sit?
Like this, see? Yeah, price comes up, hits this point.
Yeah, let me make it straight. Here, yeah.
Like this, see? Yeah, this goes down right? It already broke.
Here there are candlesticks with strong power coming in. Making price go up like this.
Boom! Then it hits this one. They can cancel each other out. It breaks if it's strong enough.
Price drops down. Drops down and hits this one. Bounces back up - but you see?
What kind is it? Strong power? Medium. So can it beat this High?
Nope. So it's lower. Then hits this one. Here doesn't have enough power.
Light, weak force. So it can't make a new Low.
See? Until finally it hits this one.
Action and Reaction. Action this much, Reaction stronger.
So it breaks upward. Makes this price shoot up.
Breaks through the range and continues following the original trend.
That's how it works. Based on understanding.
When applying it. But another type is what?
Could be sideways like - um - what kind?
Yeah, separate first. Yeah, price comes up, sideways in a range.
Continues. Yeah, earlier was a triangle right?
This one's a box. Price comes up.
Rectangle pattern like this. Running in a box.
Same thing. Yeah, price comes...
When it's running in a box, means there's nothing...
Clear in either direction.
Not enough power until it hits one that has enough power like this.
Simply put - when comparing, this one has more power than this one.
So when these two could never pass resistance...
But when this one arrives - Action, Reaction says it has power - so it pushes price through upward.
Remember? It has to happen at the same time. And it has to happen at new times.
Has to encounter this type.
This is the continuation pattern. We're talking about uptrends where price continues like this.
Where this part might just be a simple pullback, or price complexity right here - consolidating as sideways, in a box. Whatever box pattern it is.
Getting it? Now what other patterns are there? This is continuation - both up and down. When it goes down it's the same thing.
You apply the same principles. Exactly the same.
So I'm just talking about one side first - the upside. The other side just reverse the thinking.
Now another one - this continues right? Another one is it DOESN'T continue.
Boom! Goes down.
It can't continue. Hits strong resistance.
What should happen? It tries but doesn't have enough power.
Doesn't form this one even once. But the top side comes back with more power.
This one isn't enough. Can't push it down.
Finally the last one pushes down. A candlestick forms.
Candlestick set - Action, Reaction - with strong Reaction power compared to the previous one.
Take the previous one. So this is the old Low - it can make a Lower Low or new Low.
The power's stronger. It's a failure to continue. Because there's what we call a reversal.
Besides this, what else? There's resistance - same as before, like this.
And what we're familiar with - double top.
So price looks the same. First one, Reaction is weak.
Second one, Reaction is stronger. And to break through like this, really strong...
Sometimes it balances. Let's go look. Could have way more power.
Like this. Just breaks straight down.
Getting it?
It'll be like this. No matter which pattern - all the same.
Could be like this.
What's this? Head and Shoulders, see? Exactly the same.
It's simple - it'll be right here, this set.
This set makes it fail - right here.
Something like this. This one doesn't have power - didn't meet this one, ended up here instead.
It doesn't have it. It's a different one. After this one, only goes up this much.
Can't beat the previous High, the earlier High. But this one can beat the previous Low.
So price drops - adjusts downward like this. Reverses like this.
This is how to apply it.
So how many patterns do you know now?
Whether it's at the top - a Top, right?
Bottom's the same.
What else? Head and Shoulders.
Or Inverted Head and Shoulders.
Including triangles.
Like this.
Or flags, or whatever.
It all follows these rules.
You need to observe the characteristics of the candlesticks forming.
Including reading combined with other things.
That we learned from Season 1 and Season 2.
Whether it's about Momentum.
All of that.
The story - what story does it tell?
What clues does it leave?
Sometimes we don't find other clues.
Or maybe Momentum is unclear - can't read it.
But are there signals showing us like this?
This is what we use to read additionally.
Decode more.
Not memorizing it has to be like this to go down.
Understanding WHY it goes down.
Because Reaction only has this much.
But when Action wins...
It closes lower than this one.
So there's downward pressure.
If it's an uptrend...
The side that's about to reverse down.
Until it can beat the previous Low.
Then forms a new Low.
Opposite for uptrends.
It has power.
Enough power to beat...
The previous High.
Right here.
Goes up to make a new High.
Same thing, see? Higher than here.
This is Reaction.
Better if we compare to real charts.
We'll understand even better.
Alright?
About this much you should get it.
These are the patterns.
When using them, we don't memorize...
Or understand it as...
Look at whether it's strong force...
Medium or weak.
Look at the Reaction side.
Because we want to know Reaction.
And Action is part of it too.
In various patterns - which will already be at different points.
Whether it reverses a lot, reverses a little - it's all there. We consider everything.
Remember all its components. What does it need?
Like this - one, two, three, four, five - how many rules? Various criteria. Can't remember? Go back and listen.
About that much. Next episode we'll look at real chart examples.