Alright, Episode 2! We already know we're comparing this to a balance scale, right? So how many patterns does a balance scale have?
When I say "patterns," I don't mean what it looks like - I mean the different ways this balance scale can measure forces. What kind of readings can we get?
Basically, one side starts having more weight than the other.
And then we get a second scenario like this.
What's this side?
Which side is this?
Action and Reaction - what is this side?
Action is stronger - the Action force is greater than the Reaction force.
This one's balanced. Pattern one - already covered.
Pattern two and pattern three. Pattern three is basically - yeah - Action and Reaction, what's this side?
Reaction has the stronger force. Now I'm talking about just one direction here.
Like a downtrend - coming down, down, down, and then you see this pattern - a group of candlesticks forming.
Like this. And then it goes up like this - reverses. If it was an uptrend...
Uptrend reversing to downtrend - just flip it to the opposite. But right now...
Everyone getting this? Doesn't matter what direction - this side that acts first...
We call it Action. When it bounces back, that's the Reaction.
So Action on this side - the action comes out. These candlesticks are selling pressure.
Pushing down, down, down continuously. Then it hits andås back like this.
From a Pin Bar pattern like this, the Reaction forms.
Whether it's big or small, we'll need to examine that. For now, we're learning the theory first.
We've got Action and Reaction on two sides like this - kind of like this. If I draw it simpler for you...
It'll look something like this. But is this complete yet?
Not yet, folks. Let's see what else we need.
What we're looking for - first thing is, we need to identify Action and Reaction.
Second, it has to have TWO sides. So this is the candlestick pattern...
That we're after. Since we need it, we gotta count it, right?
It needs specific components - one, there has to be a candlestick here.
The middle candlestick - that's the axis of our balance scale.
Right? We need the axis - the central pivot point.
And we need arms on both sides, right? Otherwise we can't measure the forces or weights.
So we need candlesticks like this. Bottom line - we need at least three candlesticks total.
But what if it looks like this instead? Does it work? Not yet.
We still need the axis. Earlier we had an axis like this.
Dividing two sides. This side we already know - left side from now on is Action.
Right side is Reaction. And we need candlesticks - we need arms on both sides.
So we need candlesticks on either side of the center one.
Two sides - one, two, three. But that's not enough. We just learned that sometimes it flows.
Hits this pattern and flows - it doesn't form on this side.
When it flows like that, we're missing the fourth element.
What's the fourth element? Right here - what needs to happen is in this zone.
Support and resistance. Yeah, we've got the scale, we've got two arms.
And it's happening in this area - right in this zone.
This is what's occurring.
And we're gonna count - yeah, I could call it "five" if you want.
These are things to memorize. I'm calling them "things to remember."
You need to understand them and memorize them. Better than just calling them "rules." So rule five is...
We're gonna count price on the axis candlestick. Let's talk about the axis first.
The axis - yeah - no matter what it looks like, whatever the shape...
The one that's in the middle and occurs at resistance - we count the LOWEST point.
This is a key rule. Count the lowest point - that means INCLUDING the wick.
Right now there's no wick showing. Or maybe there is one - doesn't matter.
If there's a wick like this, we count this as the lowest point.
This wick here - take the lowest point first.
You might ask, "Why are we counting this?"
It's not counting like one, two, three, four, five - I mean, what do we call it?
It's an important reference point we need to keep track of.
How we're gonna use it? Let's look.
We keep this point first. This one here - we include the wick, remember?
Just for the axis candlestick. Next rule, or next point...
The next point is about the arms.
Got it? We have the axis, and we need the arms of the scale.
For the axis - right here - we count the LOWEST price point of that candlestick.
That specific one, including the wick. But for the arms - the arms on the Action and Reaction sides...
We count ONLY the candlestick body. Even if it has a wick...
Count ONLY the body. Just the body, alright?
No matter what it looks like, same rule - just the body only.
Only the body. Even if the wick is this long or whatever.
Don't count it. Body only - just the body.
So how many rules do we have now? These are things we need to remember.
Hold on, there's more. Not done yet.
We're also gonna use this criterion too - because of this...
I'm not just teaching Forex here. This can be used in ANY market.
Whether it's Forex, stocks, gold, oil - whatever.
So I need to explain it inclusively like this.
Because sometimes people might get confused, like "The chart would never look like that!"
Some markets that aren't currency or Forex - it can happen.
The chart can move however it wants.
But in Forex, when it opens and closes, it connects perfectly. But other markets might have gaps and all that stuff.
So the next criterion is - the body of the arms, on both sides. The arms - the bodies...
Find the 50% mark. 50% - half of that body. Don't count the wick - I already said, don't count wicks.
Take half. Half - no matter how small or big it is.
Take half. You might ask, "What do we do with this half?"
Compare that half to the axis. The axis candlestick.
How do we compare? Take this one - it's specific to the axis, gotta separate them out.
Even if the top part is really long, we don't count it. Count this part.
Count the body separately. And this body extends out to both sides.
Like an axis like this. And then the arms extend straight out like this.
All along these arm lines - all the candlesticks along these arm lines...
That we're counting as arms of the balance scale...
They must exceed 50%.
Must be more than half of the body.
This is what we'll use to consider and analyze things.
Like for example, this one - it looks like this.
Where's the halfway point of this one?
Half is still right here. See how it's lower than this point?
Lower, yeah. So this candlestick we WON'T consider.
I'm using the word "consider" here. This one works. This one works.
But this one? Half is here - lower than this. This one doesn't count.
Getting it? Can you visualize? Both sides - both arms.
Action and Reaction - take the ones exceeding half. Count body only, not wicks.
Body only - we use just that for analysis.
Let me summarize again in a bit. What do we have so far?
So Action and Reaction - we'll get a gain roughly like that.
Okay, let's count them up. How does it work?
First thing - what do we have? We have the axis, right? One, two, three - we have arms.
Three things so far. Then we add - support and resistance - that's four. Count the low point, include wick - that's five.
Five - count the low, include wick - five.
Yeah, and take the halfway point - that's six. Count body only.
The arms - the arms of the candlesticks - wait, the arms of the balance scale that are candlesticks - count body only.
That's seven. Seven now. Now take the price of this - the axis.
This is the axis. The axis price at the top - not the wick.
This is the measurement criterion - eight. Eight components you need to remember. Gotta remember or understand them.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight - about that many. Put them together, it'll look something like this.
Combined, we still count only the body. This one doesn't count. This one passes. Because this one doesn't reach half.
Half stops around here. See? It's lower - doesn't count.
The ones that don't count mean the power of that candlestick, whether on the Action or Reaction side...
Remember which side is which? Action, Reaction, Reaction, Reaction.
It's already absorbed by the axis. It's lower, doesn't stick out.
Means the axis absorbed it. If this is the selling side, right?
Price came down more than half like this. The price that came down...
It's already absorbed inside here. And then it bounces back up.
The price - it's still absorbed coming out. What do we call it?
Yeah, it won't all come out. Like this one doesn't count. But if it sticks out...
Breaks through and comes out already - yeah, like this - it counts.
Kind of like a magnet field, you know? Count the lowest price point and all that.
Eight things. Remember them all? Eight things. Alright, now back to this.
So besides remembering those 8 things, we're gonna go back once more to this diagram.
There are 3 patterns. See it yet?
Wait, wait - let me erase first.
Like this - what I'm about to explain.
Like this. If we see this pattern, it means price is running down and up.
Going up, right? So yeah, it goes up.
But it won't go up strongly. I'm saying "not going up strongly."
That means the Action side has more force than the Reaction side.
You ask, "More like this?" Well, it doesn't exceed it.
It can't overcome it.
This side is selling pressure - pushing down continuously.
Hits this point and goes up - the price goes up as Reaction.
But the next one that should confirm the force of the center axis...
Turns back, can't beat this side.
That means the force is weaker.
So this Reaction side loses.
When it loses, it doesn't have enough force to go far up.
So it'll only go up a little. As for this one - it's relatively...
Balanced - goes up too. Honestly, we can say it goes up stronger.
Than this one. And this one definitely goes up the strongest.
More than this and more than this. Because the Reaction side WINS.
Yeah, Action hits support/resistance - bounces back up higher than before.
Wins like this. There might be other candlesticks here - we don't care.
We just want the candlesticks in the set we need, that's all.
We want the balance scale to measure the power. Got it?
If we use this, ultimately it becomes these 3 patterns.
Weak force - this is weak force.
Evenly matched - balanced - relatively evenly matched. And finally wins - force is much stronger.
Reaction side - force is much stronger.
Simple balance scale - there are only 3 patterns. That's it - equal.
Action side is stronger.
Reaction side force is much stronger, heavier. That's all there is - nothing more than this.
Now you ask, "How do we start using this?" Once we know this, how do we apply it, right?
Let's look at that.
When using it - use it like this.
Say we look at this diagram. This one, alright? We're trading and we see price running like this.
Action, got it? Action, Reaction going up.
We're gonna buy. If you learned Momentum from Season 1...
You would...
Some people already got to buy inside the candlestick wick - got a good price.
But this one here - this section is what we call the SAFEST entry point.
You might have to wait. Instead of getting in right here, you might have to wait - wait for this candlestick.
We wait for all 3 to complete first - there's the center axis, there's the arm, there's the arm.
When it confirms it's gonna continue - wait, not continue - it's gonna reverse like this.
We can enter on the next one. Enter on the fourth candlestick, and we open...
The price to continue. But it's kind of... see?
When it confirms, it won't - it won't - yeah, it won't.
So when we enter, let it run until it hits support/resistance and sees another set on the opposite side.
Like Action-Reaction again. That's it. Place Stop Loss below the low price here. This is how we use it.
I'll explain the theory first - then we'll go into real charts and you'll understand better.
Or if there's a lot here - same amount or more than here - it gets broken and fails - price might not continue.
It becomes a reversal period coming down like this too. Because remember, when price runs, it has to run like this - remember?
And this - there'll be sideways when patterns haven't formed yet. Can't tell at all if this is sideways or not.
Why? It could become a reversal point like this already. But if it's sideways, it continues to this one.
Then hits the real peak, and changes direction to downtrend - continues down.
The chart talks like this. And here - it comes to this new side.
It's measuring the cycle of this, cycling on and on, cycling continuously.
So look at this point - it's the same thing.
Yeah, this spot doesn't have enough force. It becomes sideways right here.
Now we're getting into practical application.
Let's check out the next episode. We'll get into practical use - how to actually apply it.
We've covered all the theory now. Next step is practical application.