Let's take a look at stocks, because it also works with stocks the same way.
Let's try switching to Apple. I prepared this earlier because these two sections are quite similar. They're both three-peak patterns exactly the same.
Same pattern, see? But why did one go up and the other go down? Let's take a look. At this point.
Just remember this image first. Okay, same pattern. Let's look at this point first. Zoom in.
If you just look at this, when price came up to this point, same as before. We find the swing. Price swung up here.
This one is the highest peak on the right. And it's right here.
Look, is there Action? Here's the Action, rising strongly. Reaction is this one.
This one isn't it, it must be this color. See? They're evenly matched.
So at this point, is there a lot of Reaction force going down? Not a lot. There's little, not enough to go down significantly.
It came down about this much. Do you remember the formula? The formula, if it becomes a pattern like this.
Suppose it becomes a Triple top, right? At this point there must be little force going down. Little down force, but a lot of Reaction force. Going down a lot, that's when it breaks out.
Let's see how it turns out. It's about here. Once this is done, it moves over.
So it swings to this point. This is Action Reaction going up. So it runs up.
See? It came up about the same level as before. Because at this point there's a lot of force. It keeps running up.
Coming to this point. Actually I would count this point. Count at this point.
I choose to use this candlestick. Because actually it swung up to here.
Then it came down and swung number one, like with stocks. With stocks, the price might not be exactly like forex.
It might have an open swing that comes here, it might fill the swing here first. Let's take a look.
Currently at this point. This is Action, this is Reaction. About halfway.
So you see? The force going down here isn't a lot yet. It only came down this much and went back up.
Went back up. Now we'll observe at this point. We'll get this.
This is Action, and Reaction. See? So hitting here, is it strong? It's quite strong. It is strong.
But it came down. The word 'strong' means there's a chance it could come back and beat the old Low.
Look at where it came down. Right here. Step step step step step. At this point.
It beat it, lower than that. Which is at this point. So we'll count this point as where it bounced back up.
So here becomes the axis. But look at this point.
See at this point? This exceeds halfway, so we count it. It goes up, up up up.
And then slams down. At this point, on this side we can barely find it. We'll find it again here.
Is there Reaction? There's no Reaction. This one doesn't exceed. See? Just this much isn't enough. So it didn't go up at all. It went down further.
So it went down further because the upward force, the upward Reaction force, there's nothing to push it up at this point.
It went down further. Because if we follow our Momentum, the downward force is still a lot.
The selling force slammed down this much. And when we measure Action Reaction from here, it's a lot, you see? The Reaction side is a lot.
Its force is still strong downward like this. It came up, came up, came up. Didn't reach here. Not enough force.
We measured earlier. It came down. But it didn't go up at this point. Until it came down to here. This is another swing.
When it gets to this point, what is this? Action Reaction is here, see that it's higher?
When comparing this point with this point, or this one with this one, this is Reaction that has much stronger force than before.
So the price will run upward, and rush up. This high beats it, it's very strong, so it takes this High, not this High.
This is the answer. Not taking this High, this is the latest High. At this point.
At this point there's already a chance to beat it from here going up. But the question is, why at this point?
You have to look at this too. It's called looking at its distance. About this much for one. And from here to another one.
See that the distance is about the same? Evenly matched, close to each other. So we'll count it as a quasi-cycle. As a cycle.
As a recurring pattern. One wave here, one wave here. That it should go up.
So I count at this High. It has a chance to rally up. This one counts as resistance for sure. Hits hits hits at this point.
This is the point we'll look at again. Where it went Sideways and stuck. The third one might have to go down like this.
Let's find out, at this third range, is there anywhere hitting strongly down? That would break down from here like this.
So it would become a Triple top. After it swung down, we have to move to this one.
The line is right here. So when price fell to this red one, this block becomes Action, while the green becomes Reaction at this point.
Price will surge up. It has to go down further. Beat this High going up. Down down down.
I'll tell you that in the end, from this point, the price here is quite a lot. The force sending here is quite a lot.
It will bring the price running up until it reaches this level. According to the force being strong from here already.
In a close cycle. Let's go back. Starting from this point, right?
See? It'll be close to each other. Price runs up to about this range exactly.
Now it will break out to another one at this point. At this point it zigzags. You have to try to analyze this, at this point.
Here, going up. The one hitting down is at this point. Here's the one going up. Like this, so it couldn't go up much.
Came down to this point. At this point the force is stronger. Stronger than here. So it could come up to this point. Beat this High.
Because at this point it has higher force than here. And at this point it beat it too.
It's not saying it will go up this much. But it does beat the old High. The latest one is right here. How much?
From this point. See? Measuring the green here, Reaction won. It went up.
But from the big one, at this point that says it must go up and beat this High already, it came up all the way to this one.
When it gets to this point, we know the same thing. This means at this point, the third point of this one must be the strongest. It must be around here.
Let's take a look. Now let's look at this peak first. This peak. We'll use this one.
Is there Action? There is Action. Action is here. Action real time, Reaction that exceeds halfway.
It gets about this much, about this one, about halfway, but here it's right here.
See that it's very different from this? So can it go down strongly? It can't go down strongly. It only came down this much.
Going up further. Going up further, which line will it get? It'll get this one, at this point.
The Action side. This will be this one. The Reaction will be this one. It already exceeds halfway. They match.
See? Is the force enough? It's not enough to come down this much. Not at all, it's less than before.
This one is still at this point. One is at this point. Both are little. Both are little, so swinging to this point.
Here it went down little. It only managed to get this much. But when you look at this point. At this point.
And this is Action, we'll get this green here. While Reaction is this red that fell down.
See that it's a lot? From little, a lot at this point. Strong force falling down all the way to here. All the way to here.
Once it reaches here, can it continue going down right away? If it's going to continue down, it should be, what's it called, rally up a bit.
Come down like this and go up, then at this point it has to be strong again and fall down further.
But here it fell down. At this point it supported it. Like this. Can it go up strongly?
This one, when it came up, will it become an uptrend continuing? At this point when it came up, you see? These three.
One two three peaks, and it continues up. At first we didn't know. At this point we didn't know. In hindsight it has to be three peaks. Peak one, peak two.
Peak three, then continue up? We have to look at this point. Mostly at this point, will it go down strongly? We already know it goes down strongly.
Because it's stronger than the previous two times. So it slammed down this far. But it supports here.
It's around the support level. Fell and might go up. Let's look at its force. At this point it becomes Action.
And Reaction is this one. Can it fight? It can't fight. It can't fight, so it goes up little.
It came up just this much, doesn't beat this High. Simply put, whether it goes up little or a lot.
If you can't guess, it still doesn't beat the old High. It still goes, runs but still doesn't beat the old High.
Slams down. Meets this one. Swings a bit. Slams down. Is there strong downward force?
This is the Action force, and the Reaction force of this one, because this one doesn't exceed halfway.
So we take this one. It's still less than this. Doesn't go down at all, see? Somehow it doesn't flow down.
Huh? Or is it still an uptrend? Goes up again, where does it meet? The High before swinging down.
It must be this one. It already broke down. See? Look at the Reaction, it's still little. This one is little too. Is this one going down?
Not yet down. Huh? Or will it go up? So, it came down to this one. This one still says it won't go up.
Because, see that this green and this red, this green doesn't beat this. It still can't go up. Still can't beat the High.
If I want to try drawing a line, a bit, it would be about this. Resistance level right around this area.
Coming down. Can it go up strongly? If it goes up strongly, it can't go up again. How?
Stuck here, there's no force to go up. Cannot beat the High. Because it came up this swing and fell down.
Suppose we only see up to here. Can we still measure it yet? Because we don't know the swing point yet, right?
Action must be this candle already. The green Action that becomes Action continues behind.
While Reaction will become this one. See? It becomes that at this point it's a lot now.
Previously it wasn't a lot yet. There's this one point where it's a lot. Then it fell here. So it broke out.
You broke out. Actually, can we count it as a downtrend? We can count it already. HIGH-LOW, LOWER-HIGH, LOWER-LOW, LOWER-HIGH.
Next doesn't need to be LOWER-LOW already. If we put them together, this we talk just casually about candlesticks and everything.
Which is ACTION and REACTION, we just look at this much. If anyone looks more than this, you see many more signals already.
As for those who learned Season 2, you see this wave series. You already know what the future will be. Very precisely for sure.
And this one comes to confirm it makes you play more accurately. Let's look at this. See? ACTION and REACTION.
Because at this point it's a lot. This is a lot of force going down. And in the end where did it go down to?
It has to go down and beat the old Low already. So it goes down, flows down. About this much, see the difference between the two periods.
That have the same pattern exactly. Both are three heads exactly the same. But one it doesn't take down. It takes up.
But at this point it says take down. Because you see the points are different. The balance measurement that it says.
Here, price runs up, runs up, runs up. Does it say anything? Why does price keep running up?
Uh, let's look at the daily chart instead. Let's look at the daily. See?
Here, price was running running running running running around this area. And then it ran up.
Which point made it run up? Starting from beating this High. You look at this one.
See? Here is the lowest. Measure it. This is its axis. Action Reaction.
See clearly? See that it beats this? Anyway it will beat this High for sure. From this series.
It's already telling if you can see and read. That's all. It has traces. There are still many more today.
But it might not be told in this class. This one just takes this topic, see that it says, here, anyway it will exceed.
It might come up zigzagging, not smoothly. But we have signals already that anyway it will reach. It came to reach until achieved.
To summarize, came down to rest according to normal price patterns. And then continue. That's all.
If we look in periods, came up, came down. Now will it break, will it be able to go up again?
At which point? At this point. See? It still can't go up. See? The force is better than before.
At this point? Counting this one. See? Red. Action still beats. So it couldn't go up far. Not past this point yet.
Came up. Fell to this point. Count, this swing counts new. This swing has good force. Going up, it goes up.
Strong hitting on the ladder, will it slam down? The downward hitting force, it's not a lot. Here it's not a lot. So it doesn't take down, that's all.
Now at this point. This is Bitcoin. Crypto can still be used. Already said that the technique can be used everywhere if you can read.
Does it beat? It beats. Goes up. Done. No tricks. See? Candlesticks don't trick. Price doesn't trick.
You just know what it is, the price source. That's all. But the graph you see, you see like, see casually like this.
You know what? What is it saying? Can't see it at all. Suppose we haven't seen the next period yet.
Where to look? This one is big red. This one is big green. Directly, do they cancel each other or what? All confused.
This is the way to look. One part. In this part. The part before this, part one, you read momentum.
Did the small beat the large, fight each other? Couldn't fight, so it keeps going up. This big green has high force.
You follow the story. It tells a story, how it came. Those who learned Season 2 came. You look at this, it's a secret inside.
Says how it is. Actually from this series, it already says that price will continue up.
Those who learned Season 2, you'll know in advance already. That's all. Okay?
So that you understand, you'll have complete components. The more you use this part and that part, whoever learns a lot is better off.
Learn everything completely, you bring them to combine together. You'll read the chart much better than others for sure.
From all these secrets. All these secrets. I wish you good luck.
This green doesn't beat this.
It still can't go up. Still can't beat the High.
If I want to try drawing a line, a bit.
It would be about this.
Resistance level right around this area.
Coming down. Can it go up strongly? If it goes up strongly, it can't go up again.
How? Stuck here, there's no force to go up. Cannot beat the High.
Because it came up this swing and fell down. Suppose we only see up to here.
Can we still measure it yet? Because we don't know the swing point yet, right?
Action must be this candle already. Action.
The green that becomes Action continues behind.
While Reaction will become this one. See?
It becomes that at this point it's a lot now. Previously it wasn't a lot yet.
There's this one point where it's a lot. Then it fell here.
So it broke out. You broke out.
Actually, can we count it as a downtrend? We can count it already.
HIGH-LOW, LOWER-HIGH, LOWER-LOW, LOWER-HIGH.
Next doesn't need to be LOWER-LOW already.
If we put them together.
This we talk just casually about the candlestick set and everything.
Which is ACTION and REACTION.
We just look at this much.
If anyone looks more than this, you see many more signals already.
As for those who learned Season 2, you see this wave series.
You already know what the future will be. Very precisely for sure.
And this one comes to confirm it, makes you play more accurately.
Let's look at this. See? ACTION and REACTION.
Because dragging this down a lot.
This is a lot of force going down.
And in the end where did it go down to? It has to go down and beat it.
Look at the old one first. It goes down, flows down.
About this much, see the difference between the two periods that have the same pattern exactly.
Both are three heads exactly the same. But one it doesn't take down. It takes up.
But at this point it says take down. Because you see the points are different.
The balance measurement that it says. The weight it gives.
Here, price runs up, runs up, runs up. Does it say anything?
Why does price keep running up? Uh, let's look at the daily chart instead.
Let's look at the daily. Good.
See? Here, price was running running running running running around this area.
And then it ran up. Which point made it run up?
Starting from beating this High. You look at this one. See? Here is the lowest.
Measure it. This is its axis.
Action Reaction, see clearly?
See that it beats this? Anyway it will beat this High for sure. From this series.
It's already telling, just can you see and read?
That's all. It has traces. There are still many more today. But it might not be told in this class.
This one just takes this topic, see that it says, here, anyway it will exceed.
It might come up zigzagging, not smoothly. But we have signals already that anyway it will reach.
It came to reach until achieved. To summarize, came down to rest according to normal price patterns. And then continue.
That's all. If we look in periods, came up, came down. Now will it break, will it be able to go up again?
At which point? At this point. See? It still can't go up. See? The force is better than before.
At this point? Counting this one. See? Red. Action still beats. So it couldn't go up far.
Not past this point yet. Came up. Fell to this point. Count, this swing counts new. This swing has good force.
Going up, it goes up. Strong hitting on the ladder, will it slam down?
The downward hitting force, it's not a lot. Here it's not a lot.
So it doesn't take down, that's all. Now at this point.
This is Bitcoin. Crypto can still be used.
Already said that the technique can be used everywhere if you can read.
Does it beat? It beats. Goes up. Done. No tricks.
See? Candlesticks don't trick. Price doesn't trick.
You just need to know how to read the clues that price is showing you.
That's all. But the graph you see, you see like,
see casually like this. You know what? What is it saying?
Can't see it at all. Suppose we haven't seen the next period yet.
Where to look? This one is big red. This one is big green.
Directly, do they cancel each other or what? All confused.
This is the way to look. One part. In this part.
The part before this, part one, you read momentum.
Can the main force on this side fight back? They can't win, so it keeps going up.
This big green has high force. You follow the story. It tells a story, how it came.
Those who learned Season 2, you look at this, it's a secret inside.
Says how it is.
Actually from this series, it already says that price will continue up.
Those who learned Season 2, you'll know in advance already.
That's all. Okay? So that you understand, you'll have complete components. The more you use this part and that part, whoever learns a lot is better off.
Learn everything completely, you bring them to combine together. You'll read the chart much better than others for sure.
From all these secrets. All these secrets. I wish you good luck.