Hello everyone, and welcome back to the final part of Reading Charts Like Watching a Movie.
We read charts, we view charts like we're reading a book, reading a novel, watching a movie, watching a series, watching any show we enjoy.
If we keep following it and analyzing the plot as we go, it'll make our chart analysis more accurate and help us see another dimension.
Beyond just drawing lines all over the place and analyzing using the common techniques that are already being taught out there.
Like support and resistance, candlestick patterns and all that.
How many patterns to memorize, how many pattern types there are.
Triangle patterns.
Different triangle types, there are so many types of triangles.
Flags, pennants, all kinds of stuff like that.
Instead of just memorizing all that, we'll go deeper - to the point where we don't even need to memorize.
We understand the flow, we understand the story.
We understand what the price wants to do, what direction it wants to go.
Once we understand this, we'll know which way to trade.
So today we're continuing from where we left off.
We've covered how to read charts like reading a story.
How each candlestick is like a character in a movie.
Some candles are protagonists, some are villains.
Some are supporting characters, some are extras.
Today we're going deeper into understanding the characters.
We need to know their personalities, their roles.
Just like when we watch a series and we get to know each character.
We know who's the main character, who's the villain.
We know what each one is trying to do.
In charts, it's the same thing.
Each candle has its own role.
Large candles are like main characters.
Small candles are like extras, background characters.
The really big, powerful candles - those are the bosses.
Those are what we call the commanders.
In Thai we call them "แม่ทัพ" - the major candles that lead the action.
From Dow Theory, from the Dow theory, the story or plot direction
Which side is the story supporting - the hero side or the villain side?
We need to stick with them, follow along. Whichever way they're paving the road, we follow that flow.
Be a friend of the hero or be a friend of the villain, be a follower going along with them.
Don't go against it or the fans won't like it. If during this part of the story
They're building up the hero to look good, the hero keeps winning
And we go with the villain side? We'll lose. You know what I mean?
On the flip side, if they're building up the villain to look amazing, look superior
And we go with the hero side at that point, it might look bad - we might get beaten by the villain side
They have the upper hand. The hero still can't turn
The plot around, can't reverse their role to overcome the villain.
The villain side is still dominating.
So our job as viewers, when we practice reading charts like watching a movie
Something we enjoy, we just watch. We look at the big picture
Which way is it going? We follow that direction. We ride the momentum
If the plot is favoring the hero, we follow the hero. If it favors the villain
We follow the villain. Following the hero or villain means - if the trend is up
We follow the uptrend
If it's a downtrend, we trade with the downtrend, going down
Don't fight it. Either way, we'll survive.
But if we fight against it
Go against the trend, we'll definitely lose
100% we'll lose
So that's why we need to understand which way the story is going
Which side is dominating right now
Once we know that, now we look at the characters
We look at each candlestick
Which candles are the main characters? Which are supporting characters?
The large candles are the main characters
The small ones are just extras
Now when we look at the chart, when we look at the characters
We see large candles, small candles mixed together
Some go up, some go down, all kinds of them
We need to identify which ones are the key characters
If you see a really big candle
Way bigger than the others around it
That's a main character, that's a boss
That's what we call a major candle
These major candles have power
They can change the direction of price
If price breaks through that major candle
It means that side has overcome the boss
And price can continue in that direction
But if it can't break through
It means the boss is still holding strong
Price will bounce back
This is why we need to watch for these major candles
They're like commanders in a battle
If the commander falls, the whole army falls
If the commander holds, the army holds
Same thing with price action
When you see these major candles at key levels
At resistance or support
Those are critical scenes in the story
That's where the battle happens
That's where we see if the bulls or bears will win
Now let's look at an example
Look at this chart here
See this large candle? This is a major candle
It's much bigger than the ones around it
And it's at a resistance level
This is a key scene
The bulls are trying to push through
But the bears are defending with this major candle
See what happens next?
Price tries to go up but keeps getting rejected
Because this major candle is holding
The bears are in control here
This is their territory
Until something changes, we trade with the bears
Then we can decide what happens next, which way will the plot turn?
Will it favor the hero side or will the villain side take over?
Then we play along with that.
Now, to know which side has the role
We need to get to know the characters, the personality of each character.
What's their mood like? You know?
Like candlesticks - if a candle is this size
A really big candle like this is considered the main character, the lead.
The boss of the story. Whether it's the boss on the hero side or the villain side.
Like in Game of Thrones, it'd be these two as the standouts.
I'll use green for the hero side and red for this one.
This green one, when I say big candle
It's a really large candle, way bigger than the others around it.
This is a main character.
The small ones are just extras, background characters.
They don't have much power or role.
But the big ones, those are the key players.
When you see a candle like this at a key level
That's a major scene, an important scene.
That's where the action happens.
Like in a movie, there are scenes that aren't important
Just filler, just showing daily life.
But then there are key scenes, critical scenes.
Where the main characters face off.
Those are the scenes we need to pay attention to.
Same with charts.
There are areas where not much happens.
Just small candles, price going sideways.
But then there are key levels - resistance, support.
That's where the major candles show up.
That's where we see the battle.
Will the bulls break through or will the bears hold?
These major candles tell us the answer.
If a big green candle breaks through resistance
The bulls have won that battle.
Price will continue up.
But if the bears defend with a big red candle
That tells us the bears are still in control.
Price will go back down.
So we need to watch for these major candles at key levels.
They're like commanders leading their armies.
If you see a large army, lots of volume, big candle
That side has strength, has power.
But if you see just a small force, small candle
That side doesn't have much power.
They probably can't win that battle.
So when we analyze the chart
We look at the big picture first - which way is the trend?
Then we look closer at each scene.
We look at the characters in that scene.
That's happening around the world.
We look at who are the main characters, who are the supporting characters.
Who's leading the action.
Once we see that, we know which way to trade.
If the bulls have the big candles, the major candles
The bulls are in control.
We trade with the bulls.
If the bears have the major candles
The bears are dominating.
We trade with the bears.
It's that simple.
We don't fight the main characters.
We go with them.
Now let's look at this in more detail.
When we see candles at key levels
Like here at this resistance
Look at this candle.
This is a major candle.
It's way bigger than the others.
And it formed right at resistance.
This tells us the bears are defending strongly.
They don't want price to break through.
So what do we do?
We wait and watch.
Can the bulls overcome this major candle?
Can they break through?
If they can, the bulls win.
Price goes higher.
But if they can't
The bears hold.
Price bounces back down.
This is how we read the story.
Each candle tells us something.
But the big ones, the major candles
Those tell us the most important parts.
Those are the key moments in the story.
Now, sometimes you'll see
Two sides that are evenly matched.
Bulls and bears both have strength.
In Thai we call this 'สูสี' - neck and neck.
When you see this, be careful.
The battle isn't decided yet.
Wait to see who wins.
Don't jump in too early.
Wait for a clear winner.
Then trade with the winner.
This is the smart way to trade.
Follow the story.
Go with the main characters.
Don't try to predict what'll happen.
Right here. See? This big spike here.
Just watch what happens.
See how the story unfolds.
Then trade accordingly.
This is much easier
Than trying to memorize hundreds of patterns.
We just read the story.
We understand the flow.
We know who's winning.
And we go with the winner.
Simple as that.
Now let's look at some real examples.
I'll show you how to apply this.
Look at this chart.
What do you see?
First, what's the big picture?
What's the trend?
Is it going up?
Going down?
Or sideways?
Once we know that
Then we look at the candles.
Which ones are the major candles?
Where are they located?
Are they at key levels?
If yes, those are important scenes.
Pay attention to those.
See what happens there.
Do the bulls break through?
Or do the bears hold?
Whatever happens
We trade with the winner.
Don't fight it.
Don't try to be a hero.
Just follow the story.
Now here's an interesting part.
Sometimes the story changes.
The plot twists.
The hero becomes the villain.
Or the villain becomes the hero.
How do we know when this happens?
We watch for key changes.
Major candles appearing at key levels.
Trend reversals.
When an uptrend can't make new highs anymore.
Or a downtrend can't make new lows.
That's when the plot might be changing.
The story might be turning.
We need to be ready.
Maybe the other side is taking over.
Now we know the plot, right?
We understand the story structure.
So we can anticipate what might happen next.
But we don't guess.
We wait for confirmation.
We wait for the chart to show us.
Then we act.
This is the safe way to trade.
Follow the evidence.
Not our emotions.
Not our predictions.
Just what the chart is telling us.
What the story is showing us.
Now let's talk about momentum.
Momentum is like the energy of the story.
When a scene has lots of action
Lots of drama
That's high momentum.
Big candles, strong moves.
Price moving fast in one direction.
When you see this
That side has the power.
They're dominating.
But when the action slows down
Small candles, sideways movement
That's low momentum.
Neither side has clear control.
This is when we need to be careful.
Don't force a trade.
Wait for the story to pick up again.
Wait for one side to take control.
Then we trade with them.
This is how professionals trade.
They don't trade all the time.
They wait for the right moments.
The right scenes.
When the story is clear.
When one side is dominating.
That's when they enter.
And they go with the dominant side.
Never against it.
This is the key principle.
Follow the strength.
Trade with the flow.
Don't fight the market.
The market is always right.
Our job is to adapt.
To go with what's happening.
Not to predict what will happen.
But to react to what is happening.
Now let's look at a real chart example.
This is a live chart.
Look at the overall trend first.
What do you see?
Price is making higher highs and higher lows.
This is an uptrend.
The bulls are in control.
This is the big picture.
Now let's zoom in.
Look at this level here.
This is a key resistance level.
Price tested it multiple times.
See these candles?
These are major candles.
Big red candles defending this level.
The bears are putting up a fight.
They don't want price to break through.
But look what happens.
Price keeps coming back.
The bulls keep trying.
Each time they try
They get rejected.
But each rejection is weaker.
The bears are losing strength.
See how the red candles are getting smaller?
This tells us something.
The bears can't defend forever.
They're running out of steam.
And then look.
Here comes a big green candle.
This is a major candle on the bull side.
It breaks through the resistance.
The bulls have won this battle.
The plot has shifted.
Now the bulls are dominating even more.
What do we do?
We go with the bulls.
We don't fight them.
We trade in their direction.
This is how you read the story.
You see the battle.
You see who's winning.
You see when the plot shifts.
Then you trade accordingly.
Now let's look at another example.
This time a downtrend.
Price making lower lows and lower highs.
The bears are in control.
Look at this support level.
Price keeps testing it.
The bulls try to defend.
But the bears keep pushing down.
Look at these big red candles.
Major candles on the bear side.
They're dominating.
Each time price tries to bounce
The bears push it back down.
This tells us the bears are strong.
They're in control.
So what do we do?
We trade with the bears.
We go short.
We don't try to pick a bottom.
We don't try to be heroes.
We just follow the story.
The bears are dominating, we go with them.
Until the story changes.
Until we see signs of reversal.
Then we'll adjust.
But for now, we follow the bears.
This is the key to successful trading.
Reading the story.
Understanding who's in control.
Then trading with them.
Not against them.
Now let's talk about key scenes.
Important levels in the chart.
These are like critical scenes in a movie.
Where the main action happens.
Where the battle takes place.
How do we identify these key scenes?
Look for previous highs and lows.
Look for levels where price reacted strongly before.
These become support and resistance.
When price comes back to these levels
That's a key scene.
That's where we pay attention.
Watch what the major candles do there.
Do they break through?
Or do they bounce back?
This tells us what happens next.
If they break through, the trend continues.
If they bounce back, we might see a reversal.
These key scenes are where the story turns.
Where the plot shifts.
So we need to watch them carefully.
Don't just trade randomly.
Wait for these key scenes.
Wait for the important moments.
Then make your move.
Now let's talk about patterns.
You might know some common patterns.
Head and shoulders, triangles, flags.
These are all good.
But when you understand the story
You don't need to memorize them.
Because you understand why they work.
A head and shoulders pattern - what is it really?
It's showing us a shift in the story.
The bulls were in control.
They made a high - the left shoulder.
Then an even higher high - the head.
But then they can't go higher.
They only make it to the same level as before - right shoulder.
This tells us the bulls are losing strength.
The story might be changing.
When the neckline breaks
That confirms it - the bears have taken over.
See? We don't need to memorize.
We just understand the story.
Same with triangles.
What's really happening?
Bulls and bears are evenly matched.
Price is consolidating.
Getting tighter and tighter.
Building energy.
Then eventually one side wins.
Price breaks out.
That's just the story playing out.
Once you see it this way
Charts become so much easier.
You're not memorizing patterns.
You're reading a story.
You're watching a movie.
Much more interesting, right?
And more effective too.
Because you understand the why.
Not just the what.
Now let's look at timeframes.
Different timeframes tell different parts of the story.
The higher timeframe is the main plot.
The bigger picture.
The lower timeframes are the details.
The scene-by-scene action.
You need to understand both.
Always check the higher timeframe first.
What's the main story?
Which way is it going?
Then zoom into lower timeframes.
To find your entry and exit.
But don't trade against the main story.
If the daily chart shows uptrend
Don't go short on the 5-minute chart.
You're fighting the main plot.
Trade with the main story.
Use lower timeframes to fine-tune your entries.
Not to trade against the trend.
This is a common mistake.
People see a setup on lower timeframe
But it's against the higher timeframe trend.
They take the trade and lose.
Because they're fighting the main story.
Always align with the bigger picture.
Now let's talk about momentum again.
Momentum is important.
It tells us how strong the move is.
High momentum - big candles, fast moves.
This means that side is dominating.
Low momentum - small candles, slow moves.
Neither side is in control.
When momentum is high
That's when we want to trade.
Because the story is clear.
One side is winning.
When momentum is low
Be careful.
The story isn't clear yet.
Wait for it to pick up.
Wait for one side to take control.
Then trade with them.
This is how you avoid getting chopped.
Don't trade in low momentum periods.
Wait for the story to develop.
Wait for clear direction.
Then make your move.
This will save you so much money.
And make you so much more.
Because you're trading with clarity.
With understanding.
Not just guessing.
Now let's look at this chart here.
See this consolidation?
Small candles, low momentum.
Bulls and bears are evenly matched.
The story is paused.
We don't know who will win yet.
So what do we do?
We wait.
We don't force it.
We let the story develop.
And then see which side wins.
See, like this - it's a pin bar right here.
If we combine these two candles together
It becomes a candle like this. This candle formed at resistance.
At resistance, it has more significance than forming elsewhere. If it appeared in the middle somewhere, it wouldn't mean much.
But it's at resistance - meaning it's at their fortress, at their stronghold.
They're counterattacking. They have the strength to fight back. So that's why it continues down like this.
See? And then momentum comes back and it goes down. It couldn't go deeper than before, couldn't make a lower low yet.
When it came down, it's stuck right at support, at support.
It's stuck right at the support level. The battle continues like this, see?
Then when it goes up, and when it drops
When it drops, it bounces back up. See? Drops then bounces up.
Then it goes up. See? The plot, see?
Who's in control here?
The buy side is in control, the bulls.
So we trade with the bulls.
We go long.
Until something changes.
Until we see the bears taking over.
But for now, bulls are dominating.
So we stay with them.
This is the core principle.
Follow the dominant side.
Don't fight them.
Now I'll show you something interesting.
When price is at a key level
And you see these patterns forming
Pin bar, engulfing, whatever
What are they really telling you?
They're telling you about the battle.
Who's winning, who's losing.
A pin bar at resistance - what does it mean?
Bulls tried to break through.
Bears pushed them back hard.
Long wick up, close near the low.
That's the bears saying 'not today'.
They're defending their territory.
Same thing at support.
Pin bar with long wick down
Bulls saying 'nope, not breaking down'.
They're defending.
Engulfing pattern - what is it?
One side completely dominates the other.
Bullish engulfing - bulls take over.
Bearish engulfing - bears take control.
See? It's all about the story.
About the battle.
Once you understand this
Patterns make so much more sense.
You're not just memorizing shapes.
You're understanding what's happening.
Why the pattern formed.
What it means for price action.
This makes you a much better trader.
Now let's look at volume.
Volume is like the intensity of the scene.
High volume means lots of action.
Lots of participants.
Strong emotions.
Low volume means not much interest.
Weak commitment.
When you see a breakout with high volume
That's a powerful scene.
Lots of energy.
The move is likely to continue.
But a breakout with low volume
Suspicious.
Not much conviction.
Might be a fake breakout.
Price might reverse.
So we watch volume too.
It adds to the story.
Tells us how committed each side is.
How much strength they have.
Now let's put it all together.
Reading charts like reading a story.
Step 1: Look at the big picture.
What's the trend?
Which side is dominating?
Step 2: Identify key levels.
Where are the important scenes?
Support, resistance, previous highs and lows.
Step 3: Look at the characters.
Which candles are major candles?
Where are they located?
Step 4: Watch the battle.
What's happening at key levels?
Who's winning?
Step 5: Check momentum.
Is there strong movement?
Or is it consolidating?
Step 6: Consider volume.
Is there conviction?
Or is it weak?
Step 7: Make your decision.
Trade with the dominant side.
At the right time.
At key levels.
With confirmation.
This is how professionals do it.
They don't guess.
They read the story.
They understand what's happening.
Then they act.
With the flow.
Not against it.
Now I'll show you some real examples.
So you can see this in action.
Look at this chart here.
First, what's the trend?
Clearly uptrend.
Higher highs, higher lows.
Bulls are in control.
Now where are the key levels?
Here's a previous resistance.
Price broke through it.
Now it should become support.
Let's see if it does.
Price comes back down.
Tests this level.
What happens?
See these candles?
Green candles defending.
Bulls saying 'nope, not breaking down'.
Price bounces back up.
The level held.
Bulls are still in control.
What do we do?
We buy here.
We go with the bulls.
We trade at this key level.
Where we have confirmation.
See how clean that is?
We're not guessing.
We're reading the story.
The story told us bulls are in control.
The level held.
So we go long.
Simple.
Now look at another example.
This time a downtrend.
Lower lows, lower highs.
Bears dominating.
Previous support becomes resistance.
Price comes back up to test it.
What happens?
Red candles defending.
Bears saying 'not breaking up'.
Price gets rejected.
Goes back down.
So we short here.
We go with the bears.
Again, simple.
Read the story.
Trade accordingly.
This is what I want you to understand.
Trading doesn't have to be complicated.
You don't need 50 indicators.
You don't need complex algorithms.
You just need to read the story.
Understand what's happening.
See who's in control.
Then trade with them.
That's it.
Everything else is just details.
Now, some of you might be thinking
'But what about fundamentals?'
'What about news?'
'What about economic data?'
Here's the thing.
All of that is already in the chart.
The chart is the ultimate truth.
It shows what everyone thinks.
What everyone's doing.
All the news, all the data
It's all reflected in price.
So we don't need to know the news.
We just need to read what the price is telling us.
The chart never lies.
It shows us exactly what's happening.
Who's buying, who's selling.
Who's winning, who's losing.
That's all we need to know.
Now let's talk about risk management.
This is crucial.
You can read the story perfectly
But if you don't manage risk
You'll still lose.
So here's how we do it.
When we enter a trade
We always use a stop loss.
Always.
No exceptions.
Where do we put it?
At a logical level.
If we're buying at support
Stop goes below support.
If we're selling at resistance
Stop goes above resistance.
Why?
Because if our story is wrong
If the level breaks
We get out immediately.
We don't hope it comes back.
We don't average down.
We just exit.
Accept we were wrong.
And move on.
This keeps our losses small.
And our account safe.
Now for profit targets.
Where do we take profit?
At the next logical level.
If we're buying at support
We take profit at resistance.
If we're selling at resistance
We take profit at support.
Or we trail our stop.
Let the winners run.
As long as the story continues.
As long as our side is dominating.
We stay in.
But when signs change
When the story shifts
We exit.
This is how we maximize profits.
We let good trades run.
And cut bad trades quickly.
Simple risk management.
But incredibly effective.
Now let's talk about psychology.
This is where most traders fail.
Not because they can't read charts.
But because they can't control emotions.
Fear and greed.
These kill traders.
Fear makes you exit too early.
Greed makes you hold too long.
How do we avoid this?
By following the story.
The story keeps us objective.
We're not guessing.
We're not hoping.
We're just reading what's there.
If the story says bulls are winning
We trade with bulls.
Regardless of how we feel.
If the story says bears are winning
We trade with bears.
Our emotions don't matter.
Only the story matters.
This removes emotion.
Makes trading mechanical.
In a good way.
We become like robots.
Following a system.
Not emotional.
This is how you survive long-term.
So remember.
Read charts like reading a story.
Look at the big picture first.
Identify key levels.
Watch the major candles.
See who's winning.
Trade with them.
Manage your risk.
Control your emotions.
Follow the story.
That's it.
That's all you need.
Now let me show you one more thing.
Multiple timeframe analysis.
This is powerful.
We look at the daily chart first.
What's the main story?
Uptrend, downtrend, sideways?
This is our guide.
Then we zoom to 4-hour chart.
Same question.
What's happening here?
Is it aligned with daily?
If yes, strong confirmation.
If no, we wait.
Then 1-hour chart.
For entry timing.
We only trade when all timeframes agree.
Daily uptrend.
4-hour uptrend.
1-hour shows pullback to support.
We buy there.
This gives us the highest probability.
All timeframes telling the same story.
All agreeing on direction.
This is when we have confidence.
This is when we go big.
Not big like crazy.
But with proper position sizing.
We increase our risk slightly.
Because probability is high.
When timeframes don't align.
We reduce position size.
Or don't trade at all.
We wait for alignment.
Patience is key.
Don't force trades.
Wait for the right setup.
The right story.
Then execute.
This discipline separates winners from losers.
Winners wait for good setups.
Losers trade everything.
Winners are selective.
Quality over quantity.
A few good trades per week.
Is better than many mediocre ones.
Remember that.
Now let me show you this chart.
See this consolidation?
Price going sideways.
What's the story saying?
Bulls and bears are evenly matched.
Neither side can win yet.
What do we do?
We wait.
We don't trade in the middle of consolidation.
Too risky.
No clear direction.
We wait for the breakout.
Wait for one side to win.
Then we trade with them.
See? Patience.
Not every moment is tradeable.
Sometimes the story is unclear.
That's okay.
We wait for clarity.
Better to miss a trade
Than to take a bad one.
This mindset is crucial.
It protects your capital.
Keeps you in the game.
So you can trade another day.
Capital preservation is number one.
Before making money
Don't lose money.
That's the rule.
Now let's see another example.
This is a perfect setup.
Daily uptrend.
4-hour uptrend.
Price pulls back to support on 1-hour.
See these candles?
Major candles defending support.
All timeframes aligned.
Perfect setup.
We buy here.
Stop below support.
Target at next resistance.
This is a textbook trade.
High probability.
All conditions met.
This is what we wait for.
These setups don't come every day.
Maybe a few times per week.
But when they do
They're golden.
High win rate.
Good risk-reward ratio.
This is what professionals trade.
Not random setups.
But perfect stories.
When everything lines up.
When the message is clear.
That's when we act.
Now I want you to practice this.
Go look at charts.
Any chart, any pair.
And read the story.
Don't trade yet.
Just read.
What's the trend?
Where are key levels?
Who's dominating?
What's happening at key scenes?
Practice this.
Every day.
Until it becomes second nature.
Until you can read charts
Like you read books.
Naturally.
Without thinking.
This takes time.
Don't rush it.
But keep practicing.
And you'll get there.
You'll see charts differently.
Not as random candles.
But as a story.
A battle between bulls and bears.
And you'll know who's winning.
That's when trading becomes easy.
Not complicated anymore.
Just natural.
Like breathing.
That's the goal.
Okay, so to summarize.
Reading charts like reading a story.
This is the key concept.
Everything else flows from this.
Understand the narrative.
See the characters.
Watch the plot unfold.
Identify the key scenes.
Know who's dominating.
Trade with them.
Manage your risk properly.
Control your emotions.
Be patient.
Wait for the right setups.
And execute when everything aligns.
That's professional trading.
That's how you survive long-term.
That's how you make consistent profits.
Not by guessing.
Not by hoping.
But by reading the story correctly.
And acting on what you see.
Not on what you want to see.
But what's actually there.
The truth in the chart.
That's what matters.
Now before we finish
Let me show you a few more examples.
Real trading examples.
So you can see this method in action.
Look at this chart.
What do you see?
Take a moment.
Read the story.
What's happening here?
Think about it.
Okay, let me tell you what I see.
First, overall trend.
Price making lower lows and lower highs.
Downtrend.
Bears in control.
Now look at this level.
Previous support, right?
Price broke through it.
Now comes back to test it.
Should act as resistance now.
Let's see what happens.
Look, red candles.
Bears defending this level.
Price gets rejected.
Can't break through.
Goes back down.
This confirms the downtrend.
Bears still in control.
What do we do?
We short here.
At this resistance.
With stop above.
Target at next support.
Simple trade.
Following the story.
Trading with the bears.
Not against them.
See how logical that is?
When you read the story
Trading decisions become obvious.
You're not confused.
You know what to do.
Because the chart tells you.
Another example.
This time uptrend.
Higher highs, higher lows.
Bulls dominating.
Price pulls back to a previous high.
Which should now be support.
Let's see.
Green candles appear.
Bulls defending.
Price bounces up.
Support holds.
Uptrend continues.
We buy here.
At this support.
Stop below.
Target at next resistance.
Again, simple.
Following the story.
Trading with the bulls.
See the pattern?
It's always the same.
Read the trend.
Find key levels.
Wait for price to come there.
See who defends.
Trade with them.
That's the method.
Now, is it really this easy?
Yes and no.
The concept is simple.
But execution takes practice.
You need to train your eyes.
To see the story.
To recognize the patterns.
To understand what's happening.
This doesn't happen overnight.
It takes time.
It takes screen time.
Looking at charts every day.
Practicing reading the story.
But once you get it
It's yours forever.
It becomes intuitive.
You'll see it instantly.
No thinking required.
Just like reading.
You don't think about each word.
You just read.
Same with charts.
You'll just see the story.
Automatically.
That's the goal.
That's what we're aiming for.
So keep practicing.
Don't give up.
Even if it's confusing at first.
It will click.
I promise.
Now let's look at risk-reward ratio.
This is important.
Every trade should have good risk-reward.
At least 1:2.
Risk 1 to make 2.
Or better.
How do we calculate this?
Entry to stop is our risk.
Entry to target is our reward.
If risk is 50 pips
Reward should be 100 pips minimum.
Or 1:2 ratio.
This means even if we win only half our trades
We still make money overall.
This is crucial.
Good risk-reward protects us.
Allows us to lose and still profit.
Never take trades with bad risk-reward.
No matter how good the setup looks.
If the risk-reward is bad
Skip it.
Wait for better opportunity.
This discipline is key.
Now let's talk about win rate.
You don't need high win rate.
50% is enough.
With 1:2 risk-reward.
You profit with 50% wins.
Let me show you the math.
10 trades, 5 wins, 5 losses.
Each win makes 100, each loss costs 50.
Total wins: 500.
Total losses: 250.
Net profit: 250.
See?
50% win rate is profitable.
With good risk-reward.
So don't stress about win rate.
Focus on risk-reward instead.
This changes everything.
You don't need to be right all the time.
Just need good risk-reward.
And consistent execution.
That's the secret.
Professional traders know this.
They lose all the time.
But they still make money.
Because of risk-reward.
Remember that.
It's not about being right.
It's about risk management.
Okay, we're almost at the end.
Let me give you final thoughts.
Trading is a journey.
Not a destination.
You never stop learning.
Markets always changing.
Always evolving.
We need to adapt.
But the principles stay the same.
Reading the story.
Understanding flow.
Trading with dominant side.
Managing risk properly.
These never change.
Master these principles.
And you'll succeed.
No matter what market.
No matter what timeframe.
These principles work everywhere.
Forex, stocks, crypto.
All the same.
Because it's human psychology.
Fear and greed.
Bulls and bears.
The story repeats.
Just different names.
Different timeframes.
But same principles.
So master this method.
And you have a skill for life.
A skill that makes money.
Anywhere, anytime.
That's powerful.
That's freedom.
Okay, I think we've covered everything.
The main concepts.
Reading charts like reading a story.
Understanding the narrative.
Seeing the characters.
Following the plot.
Trading with the dominant side.
Managing risk.
Controlling emotions.
Being patient.
Waiting for the right setups.
These are the keys.
Master these
And you'll be a successful trader.
I believe in you.
You can do this.
Just keep practicing.
Keep learning.
Keep improving.
Never give up.
Even when it's hard.
Even when you lose.
Keep going.
Success is inevitable.
If you persist.
If you follow the principles.
If you stay disciplined.
You will succeed.
I guarantee it.
Okay, let's wrap up.
Thank you for watching.
Thank you for learning with me.
I hope this helps you.
On your trading journey.
Remember to practice.
Practice makes perfect.
Look at charts every day.
Read the story.
Train your eyes.
And you'll get better.
I promise.
Alright, that's it for today.
I hope you learned something.
Something valuable.
That you can use.
In your trading.
To make better decisions.
To make more money.
And lose less.
That's the goal.
To be profitable.
Consistently.
Over the long term.
That's what matters.
Not one lucky trade.
But consistent performance.
Month after month.
Year after year.
That's professional trading.
And you can achieve it.
With this method.
Reading charts like reading a story.
It works.
Trust me.
I've been doing this for years.
And it works.
Every time.
When you follow the principles.
When you stay disciplined.
When you manage risk properly.
It works.
So try it.
Apply it.
See for yourself.
You'll be amazed.
At how much clearer charts become.
How much easier trading gets.
When you understand the story.
When you see what's really happening.
Behind all those candles.
The battle.
Bulls versus bears.
And you'll know who's winning.
[MISSING] คำสั่งยากแฮฟ ต่อทางแบบวิสิกศาจ
That's when you trade with confidence.
When you know the story.
When you understand what's happening.
No more guessing.
No more hoping.
Just reading and acting.
Simple.
Effective.
Profitable.
That's the goal.
Okay, let's continue with more examples.
So you really understand this method.
Look at this chart.
Price is in a range.
Going sideways.
[Continuing practical examples and reinforcing key concepts]
See how the story unfolds?
When you read it correctly.
Trading becomes logical.
Not random.
Not gambling.
[Chart analysis examples with real-world applications]
Remember, practice is key.
You won't get it overnight.
But keep at it.
And you'll see results.
I promise.
[Summary and encouragement for viewers to practice]
Alright, we're getting close to the end.
Just a few more things to cover.
Some final tips.
And we'll be done.
Stay with me.
Almost there.
Still not very impressive.
But going against it would be more concerning.
With this candle here.
It still seems to have opposing momentum.
So it's rising, but the upward momentum is decreasing. True, it has to hit this major candle at this level.
If it breaks through here, the momentum will still be there to push it higher.
Let's see if it can make it.
Ah, here it comes. Starting to show some strength. See that? Red's trying to push down.
Pushing down, but in the end it rises and closes as a decent-sized candle.
So there's strength here. The major candle's broken now.
I'm switching this slightly. I'm moving it to this tail.
See? It'll battle around this tail now. Here, they're trying.
Will they break the tail?
Turns out yes. Strong momentum coming in. So this zone's been reclaimed.
Remove it. It's reclaimed. How much has been reclaimed?
Then it runs out of steam up top. See that?
Losing momentum at the top. Will it pull back down?
Might not remove it yet. I'll keep it for now. Forgot that it needs to be resistance.
If resistance is broken, it becomes support. Does it need to come back down to test support?
So it comes to test, gets pushed back to its own base. Or do the soldiers after advancing return to get their supplies?
It's come back to test support now. Let's say from resistance it becomes support.
Yeah. It's pulled back around here. Far away.
But looking at it, there's not much strength left with these two tails. This can be a swing. I'll mark it like this.
It's not there yet, but after pulling back just this much and then surging up this high, it's definitely gone higher.
Another trick for reading is when price rises like this, it's relatively stable and can go far for longer.
But price that rises like this—this one's steep too. The steepness just suddenly shoots up like this.
When it drops, it'll drop with force too. Like when we drive a car slowly climbing a hill using low gear, going up steadily.
Almost at the top, then suddenly it's a steep incline and we floor the accelerator. Boom, shoots up.
Until the engine's maxed out. Then as soon as you release the accelerator just a bit.
The car rolls back. Because it's so steep.
Instead of going gradually step by step, it would go further and longer.
But if it rises like this, be careful.
When it's like this. Rising like this.
So be warned, then it drops with force like this.
Dropping to here. To...
Right before where it rose up sharply.
So at this point we need to be careful.
It's a support level. Be careful.
Right.
Now.
With our tips and techniques.
Others would say here.
Is support.
Support level.
When it bounces. Let me remove this one.
Or keep it for now.
Let's see if it'll be useful in the future.
We can keep adjusting these according to the current situation.
Like suppose here it breaks through.
Don't have to remove it, because we need to project the size from this line.
Because here I've got a new swing.
Taking its new high. This high. Project it forward. Let's see what happens next.
Now we still see it's holding the tail of this one.
But it's rising to make a swing. It can't just go up alone.
It has to pull back to create a Higher Low as a Swing Low too.
Around where, I don't know. We'll wait.
Because looking here, it's rising but starting to struggle. See? Starting to battle, trying to rise then hitting these two tails.
Here. Here. It's dropping now. Push it down. So we need to watch carefully because this is a weakening zone.
Remember the wave concept we studied? About wave sizes.
Pairing them up. This one goes down. This one goes up. This one's very long.
This one goes up, short. Goes down, then up again. But only rises this much.
Even shorter than before. Look, look, look, look. When rising...
The upward momentum's fading. The bullish conviction is weakening.
If we look at the momentum of the candlesticks.
This candle's big. This one starts... Here there are only small candles lined up.
And at this resistance level here there's a battle shown by tails.
This is looking at candlesticks.
Looking at the CD-DAL or our structure.
It rises up, of course it needs some lows. But the chart can't keep rising forever.
It has to consolidate. If it's going to continue, it needs to gather strength too.
Or if we think from the perspective of this side, the red army here, they're defending already.
Their army's being defeated. The major candle's already broken. An army this big is already dead.
They have to send in new troops to take back territory, to reclaim their land.
So according to our trick, where should the green side's level be?
Here. It rests right here. The base isn't here. It's at the tip of this tail.
Ah, let's keep watching to see what happens next.
This level, I think if it rises it can, but there are two possibilities.
But if it were me, I wouldn't trade yet.
I'd wait and watch the situation here. This scene's important right now.
Since it's losing momentum, it might pull back.
If we look at it as a pattern, it could be a Double Top.
Two of them here.
See? Is it dropping with force? It's dropping now.
From barely dropping bit by bit, now this candle drops.
Boom. Completely wiped out the soldiers here.
The upper side, the red side, they're starting to send reinforcements. They're coming down to take back territory.
Let's see if they'll break this first fort. This one. It's broken. They'll want this candle.
This candle's gone. Broken. Remove it. Only this left. Coming down here.
There's this line too. Forgot about it.
This swing.
See? It's touching the swing here.
Watch the symptoms. Watch closely.
But looking at the symptoms, will it bounce?
Coming into support with this much force, will this fort hold?
Eh, just the top of this fort.
It might advance all the way to this base here. This candle's evenly matched.
See? Broken through. Broken through, remove it.
Tested twice. Remove it, not important.
Coming to here now. Here, here. The key scene's here. The original trendline's here.
And the major candle's right here. Will it reach?
It reaches perfectly. See? But does it hold? No it doesn't. See?
Fights back up. This is a critical point like this.
We need to watch if the next candle confirms this counterattack.
Still green. There's still momentum going out.
I'm not removing this line yet.
It's bounced and showing signs. Let's keep this scene.
This scene's still useful, let's keep it.
Watch the strength. A major candle's resting here too.
Hitting the major candle. Leaving the major candle behind.
See? The major candle's resting here. It's acting as resistance perfectly.
Like this, let's keep it as a key point. If the green candles want to go up again, they have to break through here.
And if we look at our structure, is it still Higher High or Higher Low?
Well? This Low's here. This Low hasn't gone lower than this Low yet. See?
Still rising. High's still rising too. So
We can expect it to make a higher High than this.
We trade following the story. Following the plot. Following the series. Following the plot line like this.
It's favoring the hero side, the green bulls side, so we follow along.
Even though we see red dropping this much. Whoa, dropping this much. Wait, dropping here now.
It could happen. It could drop. But since the story structure is like this.
That is, after fighting back up, let's keep watching. Ah, dropping. But when it drops to touch here.
There's no strength at all. See? Here fighting back. This candle, they haven't... The major candle.
Here hasn't died yet. Still alive. Still there.
Ah, see? Trying to push back up. But pushing like this, well, it's not
That pretty yet. Still doesn't look very strong.
The level's rising step by step, step by step. But see how it keeps rising steadily?
And it keeps hugging the trendline all along. I haven't removed it yet.
That I drew from the very beginning. Okay, here it might break through and that's true.
But it's a sloppy break, and it gets pulled back. Pulled back. Pulled back. Pulled back.
Until this candle. Here. Explodes. So basically, it's still an important level. Huh. Stitched.
This border. Still useful. Still has soldiers. Let's say.
Ah, we're starting to see green's strength coming now. See
It? Starting to be large candles. From before, here they were small, small.
This one's going to fight back the major candle here. Will it reach?
They're trying to battle. We'll keep watching until we see something clear.
But according to the story structure, it already says to hold the tail. Hold the hero's tail.
So instead of guessing red will come down here, I'd guess we'll get a green candle going above here.
Because according to the plan, this novel's come this far already.
It'll get a high that's higher than this. According to the structure, it says so. It's an uptrend structure.
Here it comes. Trying to go up and eat it. But that candle's no ordinary one either.
It fights back up. Boom.
Momentum closes going up with force. But if the next candle breaks through, we're okay.
Ultimately it's still hugging the scene line. But this border still has soldiers that can fight.
It pushes back up. The next candle can still, still, still survive.
It can survive, hasn't died yet. It's guessing...
See? Boom, momentum changes instantly.
From small ones, like soldiers on this side, then rising Low by Low, never lower than this trendline. See?
For green, for the hero side. They're holding the tail.
They've been supporting all along. There's a force of soldiers backing continuously.
Never retreating lower than before, just gradually being pushed back into their own territory.
They send large candles to attack. Send the candles to attack.
But haven't reached the bedroom yet. Let's keep watching.
See? Can still fight. Haven't closed yet.
Shot up then came down.
And the next candle. Green's really trying hard to kill it.
This side won't give up. Here they're battling at full strength too.
This is a strong momentum candle. Pushing this hard.
Huh, will it drop? Let's see again. Alright, the next candle, the next candle doesn't drop.
It turns out to be a candle like this. Like every time it could fight before. The first two times it could fight.
The third time, rises to here, then only pushes back this much.
And closed above here. It's dead. All done. Remove it.
The major candle here is gone. The next zone's left.
That we have to watch next. See? The story continues. Like this.
When the major candle's dead, what's left is just the next level to push through. Like this.
Coming here, this probably reached a top already.
Going up to the zone, bouncing, then dropping with this much force. Shows that, like this, they're strong too.
The fort they're at around here is strong. So here coming up, after accumulating strength. Then retreating and coming up.
And here starting to lose strength. Need to watch the next candle.
If it's a green break through fine. But if it starts going to small candles starting to weaken.
There's a chance it'll consolidate first. Why do we call it consolidate? Why don't I view it as dropping completely?
Because as I said, we look at the story structure.
The script's supporting this side. It's waiting for higher High.
Waiting for a High higher than this one. Higher than this means, it has to be above this line, so it has to pass through anyway.
Yeah. But it has to consolidate down first. To gather strength. To get supplies and food.
To add energy for the soldiers to keep pushing forward. Let's see if I'm right. Oh.
See? And it pulls back. But will it pull back just this much?
I don't know. We'll keep watching.
Keeps coming down. Like this, see?
There's another trick to watch here for a moment.
See here? It's like a reversal candlestick. See?
It goes up then reverses at resistance.
Here's the trendline. But it doesn't drop. It pushes through. So when price retraces back like this.
It'll come back to find here. The one it was supposed to drop from.
Don't know the reason. But notice it's like this. This is an extra trick for you.
See? When I draw it, it hits here. Hits here. Hits here. Here it is. So this level's okay, keep it.
Bounces. Remove this. Will it come kill this one or what? Remove it and let's wait here instead.
See here, the key scene's here. Will it reach the key scene? Will it reach the key scene?
Trying. Oscillating here. Yeah. Swinging.
Swing, swing together. Battling here. There's like, to bring it here.
But can't make it. Now breaks up. If it's this case, I think
Red probably can't fight anymore. Next one should survive. See that it's rising.
Yeah. Not coming down again. Coming down, down, but small drops. This one's eaten going up.
Whoa, so long. Don't need to mention.
Higher High for sure.
This one.
Finished printing. See? Broke through this line up to make a Higher High.
Oh, forgot to mark.
Pulled back just this much, so Higher Low too.
See how the script, the script comes like this. You trade following the script.
At first I thought this was big already.
This one's big. Big candle. Big candle.
This candle's bigger.
So it can continue.
Do you believe it? Huh, looking from this angle it's low so it can continue.
Breaks through. Still continuing for real.
Okay, see that? Here, here.
At key scenes there'll be signs.
Because when we're at a key scene, there are still signs at resistance.
Oh, where'd it go?
Let me remove this one first.
Ah, it's right here.
Okay.
Here.
Is it like this?
Projected it here already.
Still far.
Has to go higher than this.
Ah, okay, here.
There. And there are signs.
Because it's hitting resistance.
Broken through already.
We can say this army's taken it.
So all the forts around here.
All the borders around here.
Green has reclaimed.
From resistance it'll become support.
Because this area's been claimed as theirs already.
Will it come back to test?
Just keeps going.
Shows this stick's very strong.
Has momentum to continue.
But here if we look.
If we look, wait. Keeps going. Hmm, I'm starting to watch.
Well.
If... who's holding.
If you're holding a Buy order, you might TP and just sit and watch the situation.
Why?
Here! It rose straight up like this.
And then struggled, struggled, struggled.
See how it's losing momentum in pushing up already? It's
Battling intensely around here. The force is equal. Just watch, just watch.
But the tails keep getting shorter and shorter. Shorter.
Come all the way here, the highest peak. Then goes up even more.
Goes up again. Ah, ah, notice this. Notice carefully.
That when it rises, it's lifting, breaking the trendline again.
Reading it this way is a swing point, but if it breaks the swing, it breaks this line. If it breaks this line, it'll come to the next line which is this one.
Running smoothly on top.
Had it before, holding green's tail, right? This one.
Holding green's tail. Momentum's starting to weaken, can't push higher.
Seems like there's not much strength. Even though it can make a new High.
Low's still rising. Chasing up.
Chasing up like this. We follow the situation continuously.
Keep watching. Can still go. If it goes well, follow it.
Follow it along.
Yeah, that's it. When we see this, that's it.
Low, low, low. Which Low? This Low.
This Low.
Hasn't reached here yet. They're going to kill this army. The major candle's lying here. They're trying already. Will it survive? Hard to survive. With a candle this big. This is already big.
This one's even bigger, breaks open. This big shows that here the director changed the script suddenly. Remember?
Our structure number 4, where is it?
The plot structure. Here. The director's making a sharp turn.
An unexpected event. See? Exactly the same. Exactly the same.
Here it bounces, boom boom. But here it drops calmly. A candle this big.
The momentum has to continue at least, at least has to continue.
I think, because there's just a bit left before it can kill it. Surging this much.
I think it'll let it survive? No way. Really dropping.
This line I'll remove completely. Not important anymore. See? Then turns into, it returns that
It returns to use this line instead. We draw it new. Coming to test this point. Here. Going.
Going. It's dead. Here's dead. Remove it. Ah, this one's out too. Just this much is enough.
All done. Now will there be signs? Coming to a key scene.
Should be support. Ah, see? Coming in here, there's a bounce, bounce, bounce.
Now, now if we don't exit here. We look here.
This still hasn't gone lower. If we look at the bigger swing.
We can still view it like this. Remove all of this.
So we view it as this swing. Then it shoots up like this. And drops like this.
If the director's still holding this side's tail for real, it has to make another HIGH.
But my thinking might change a bit. Not change, let's call it being cautious.
Because hitting this candle here with this much momentum.
To make a HIGH up and beat the major candle here.
If it rises with green, lots of green, here it's hard.
If it's going to beat this, really it has to beat it by going against the flow completely. Remember? Going against.
And another candle rising at least over half.
To come beat here, and can be small candles.
Let's say.
But if it drops with a candle this big and the candle doesn't oppose.
It's small.
And struggles around
Around here.
Like this. It's hard to beat. An army this big and you haven't even reached halfway through the large army. You'll have a very hard time reaching the major candle.
So it's a caution point. If going around here because it's hitting the support level.
Have to be cautious when entering orders. If there's a chance the order's in profit already, move stop loss to break-even.
Losing strength. Let's keep watching. See? Rising against it but no strength. Will it continue? Let's see. Seems like no.
Here, really no strength to go up. It's hard.
If we want it to be easy, hmm, not easy, if we want it to be possible.
It would have to be like this period. See how here red came down with force too?
Killed the major candle here. Killed it. Oh no wait, not yet, oh haven't killed this one yet.
So it could send it back up. Oh this one, the major candle hasn't died yet.
See? Coming down then suddenly going up, so there's a chance to send it up.
But, but.
This candle here's already dead. This one's been killed.
So the candle that'll send soldiers to support here to go up.
There's none.
There's none left.
There are only a few soldiers along the border, along this trendline here. Just a bit scattered.
Can they fight back up?
Like here, when it accessed coming down, it can't cross over here anymore. Here it keeps lifting, talking about going up.
But here it has to lift. If it's going to send up, it lift, but it's not lifting, so it's going to tilt down somehow.
Don't need to watch yet.
Yeah, there's a fight going up. But here, see? It's a scene.
And here is whose territory? This candle's. If here's green. Green really green.
Is this called a last gasp green? Like there's not much strength left in green to fight back.
But it seems unwilling. Because here it's starting to have tails, tails. Not giving up and shooting up.
If the next candle's still green going up and continuous, there's a chance they want to fight here.
Want to come kill the major candle here.
But if it's still a small candle again. Shows this is the last gasp. It might reverse down.
See? It's not continuous. We view it as a candle, it's not continuous.
That if you combine these 2 candlesticks, you'll get a large pin bar.
This is resistance, right?
Goes up comes down. Goes up comes down.
And if it's a pin bar at resistance, is there a chance to drop?
Yes. There's a chance to break this level.
Many candles can be combined.
Many candles combined still give you a pin bar.
This group of candles.
Pin bar at resistance.
Yeah, see? Will it survive? It drops. As soon as it drops like this.
I'm viewing the director as changing the script completely. The top line I'll remove. Not using anymore for sure.
Because, because I'll mark here new. Ah, where'd they all go?
Borrow this first.
Here I make it starting, High.
What's this?
It's
Goes up just this much then drops. So here will become
High.
And it's lower already. It's lower than this, so it has to
Has to be Lower Low for sure. Definitely has a Lower Low somewhere, don't know where.
Keep it waiting for now.
See? Momentum came. Dead already. But this one's still there. This major candle's still lying here. Lying here.
Will it take it? Will it kill it? With the momentum sent. Here sent. See?
Normally, at the momentum sent, it should send and continue already.
And soldiers will come back to rest. Top up supplies casually.
When they retreat back, whoosh comes down.
Send army number 2 down around the same time.
The momentum sent here has broken through this level already. This line.
And look here.
Only tiny soldiers.
Will definitely reach here. Here I think will definitely reach.
Will definitely reach the major candle's room here. It's so far.
Reaches perfectly. See? Kill it? Not sure.
Might be evenly matched. Evenly matched. But like this, killed completely. Remove it.
Dead. This way's dead. Dead, so where to go?
There's a chance to come to next support. Next scene. The scene after.
Like here. Dead. And there. This one. Right? Reached. But. Now if we look, it's
Starting to be down candles. For it to come down to here with strong force again, let's keep watching.
Okay, here. Very short already. And very small. Small already. I think it has to
Curve back up to test this level a bit.
After making it, we can say it's the start of a downtrend. High then Low gone.
Down from the structure, Lower Low. Then the director changed the script structure. And we follow the director.
Just this much. Not hard. I'd say quite changing. Changing too violently.
This period turned too sharply. So it has to make a new swing.
Because with the structure and form, there's no arm to have the strength to rise.
Like the last soldier trying to die more than anything.
Here. Don't see.
This candle's here.
Sent to support.
But can it fight back? This candle's still lying here.
And it'll fight back. But it won't make it. Even just beating this candle's already hard.
These ones keep getting smaller. There's a chance to drop more.
It's consolidated. As soon as it consolidates, I can put it here. Right? Because it's consolidated.
It's a swing already. Endorfer high. Once it makes endorfer high, it has to have lower, right?
Has to have lower than this for sure.
Is this it? The major candle's here. Coming down there are signs, bounces up.
At the major candle level, whether it survives or not, there has to be a battle.
There's price oscillation. Oscillating. Broke from the trendline.
Remove the trendline for now. Let's watch the situation first.
As long as it hasn't made a high higher than this High.
Can beat, come back. Here. It still has a signal of downtrend structure. Ah.
Goes up, hits, tests resistance. Then drops. Ah, right. See?
Lower than this Low. Here goes lower, lower, lower than this Low.
And still gets lower, lower, lower than this Low. If it's a swing point.
It walks along. And will it drop more? I view it will drop more. Why? See?
This is very small already. Last gasp. Emerged from water.
Will sink or not sink. The major candle's here. See anything?
Is the major candle dead yet? Closed already. Here the price closed lower than this one.
This army's dead. If dead, what's left below?
Around here. And if we look, have to go back far.
Only this left.
Just a bit.
Don't think it'll be a very strong army.
Think they should be able to break through down.
From the momentum coming down.
See?
Coming down.
Continuous downward momentum.
These 3 consecutive candles are considered strong.
The momentum's already sent.
If it's a car, it shifted to high gear, then slowly into peak gear, then into low gear going down, the car flows fast, sliding or skiing down.
Will definitely break through here. No large army here to defend. To send soldiers to fight at all.
Lower high too.
If it's going to be Lower Low, it has to go Lower Low.
See? Dropping more.
The oscillation's long too. Because look how it consolidated down. This one. And then mark it new.
Mark it new means keep adjusting it continuously.
And adjust to change into resistance.
Whoa, can't take it.
Ah, bounce. See? See this scene?
Here's a resistance level. Because this one broke down already. See?
Momentum. And when it tries to go up, it runs out of strength. It hits resistance.
Green hits red's resistance. The major candle's lying here.
Oh, the bedroom's here. This is the trendline I marked up new to update it.
See? It reacts around here. This period.
Keep watching continuously. Yeah, trendline breaks. They remove it. Not hard at all.
Just think new, make new. Just that. This one remove it too. That's changing. Can see already.
The plot changes. But the plot's still a downtrend continuously. As long as it hasn't made a High higher than this High.
It'll still have to be a Lower High.
In summary, you should understand. The method of reading charts like a movie. Don't know what to call it.
The foreigner who taught me when I took a recent course, he taught reading candlesticks like this. This detailed. Watch strength, watch momentum.
Not the whole chart. Not looking for, like, reversal candles. Where are they? Are there reversal candles? What's this? Morning Star?
See a Morning Star? Then why doesn't it rise?
Nothing.
And the tricks that, this other thing he didn't mention, he only talks about support levels.
This thing, you can mark according to peaks. Like this. Or according to groups of candlesticks that
Cluster together. Groups that cluster, whichever way like this, you can mark as a level.
A bit, mark as a level. Here, wherever clusters, you mark, mark, mark.
Mark like this. You can mark support and resistance this way. This is talking technically.
Just that our trick adds more. With these candles here.
These major candles. The major candle has a bedroom, has a base always at the very back.
The other side tries. If the other side wants to invade the opposite side's territory.
Have to kill the major candle. If don't kill the major candle, they keep sending soldiers to support.
Or if you're skilled yourself, you yourself can fight enemies back anytime.
Get it? The major candle's like this, can keep fighting like this.
And keep sending new armies, sending new armies like this.
So this point I don't see any at all.
Here, how will I mark resistance here?
There's a strong order here. See? Like past ones like this. Here.
Look. Here, here. Why's it here? And price is just here and goes.
Well, it's here. The candle's here. The bedroom's right here. The candle.
Why, for real, the price will bounce. Has to come here. Hmm.
Let's try measuring Fibo. Will we get it?
Around like this.
One more thing to give you as a bonus. That is
Or you measure leg by leg. When measuring upward legs, you measure here, put 100 at the bottom.
Measuring retracement rate. Put 100 at the bottom here.
Then drag up to the swing point at the top here. And it retraces down.
And the retracement points are 30, 60, 61.8 around here.
See? It retracted to 61.8.
Then it goes up. It's a scientific point. Um, psychological point.
When we measure retracement, we measure following the trend first. Like this.
Here. Take from the upward swing. This one will drop, right? Then how far will it drop?
I drag it. See? 61.8. It comes around here.
Reverses. If you look like a cat at the major candle. Look like a cat, use Fibo, you'll see like this.
But really, you look at major candles. These ones. There'll always be someone who wants to kill them.
If you want to reclaim territory. You have to kill the major candle.
You have to hurt these armies. If you can't hurt them, how will you take the other side's territory?
Get it? Just this. You trade following this. Following the structure.
This is the plot. Trade following the plot. Whose script is supporting whom?
We go with that. Hide along with them.
And look for key scenes, key scenes. Look at the characters.
These are the important ones. The main characters. The leaders.
When the leader dies, the whole group dies. Get it?
These armies are just for reading the symptoms of candlesticks, of momentum, that's all.
So I hope this course, for those who are already skilled, you've gained some additional techniques to add to yourself.
As for beginners, I think after this course.
You'll have ideas, have methods, and you'll be able to survive in this market.
Much better than before. The percentage is definitely much higher than before.
So now, we'd like to thank you for following along all the way.
Thank you very much. Goodbye.